阿尔帕·奇诺！
Alpa Chino!
我们醉得疯狂
We're loaded
我爱BB  哦耶  我爱BB  哦耶
I love the pussy, hell, yeah
我爱  向地上流水的BB
I love that pussy dripping down to the floor, oh, no
我爱最湿的BB  我爱BB  耶
The wettest pussy, hell, yeah I love the pussy, hell, yeah
我要喝干PP流的香汗  达到高潮
I'm drinking up your Booty Sweat and busting a nut
阿尔帕·奇诺  他操控了BB
Alpa Chino got that pussy control
阿尔帕·奇诺代言的PP香汗能量饮料
Alpa Chino's Booty Sweat.
张开你的PP迎接吧
Pop an ass open!
“PP香汗能量饮料”和“高潮坚果棒”特许经营店现已销售
Booty Sweat and Bust-A-Nut bars available at concessions now.
2013年的地球  忽然就不转了…
In 2013, when the Earth's rotation came to a halt...
总统宣布  整个北美都是灾区
The President has declared all of North America a disaster area.
“我号召大伙团结一心…”
I call on my fellow Americans to come together...
…人们呼唤着能够拯救世界的英雄
...the world called on the one man who could make a difference.
当地球又不转了  他又来了
When it happened again, the world called on him once more.
可谁也没想到他又来了3次！
And no one saw it coming three more times!
现在
Now,
那个曾经5次拯救世界的男人
the one man who made a difference five times before,
再度归来  改变世界！
is about to make a difference again.
不过这次  有所不同
Only this time, it's different.
是谁没关冰箱门？
Who left the fridge open?
主演  奋力·快男
Tugg Speedman.
《热天总动员6》之全球消融！
Scorcher Vl: Global Meltdown.
再次开始吧
Here we go again.
再来
Again.
您还要点什么？
Will there be anything else?
我的帅哥  再来点豆子
Yes, my dear man. More beans.
奶奶！
Granny!
真不敢相信！
Please!
今夏  美国人气最旺的肥肥一家再次亮相
This summer, America's favorite obese family is back.
真恶心！
Gross!
-看我比你瘦  不爽了吧  -才不是呢
-You're just mad 'cause I'm skinny. -Am not!
杰夫·波特牛  扮演
Jeff Portnoy.
杰夫·波特牛主演的  《肥仔之家：第2屁》
And Jeff Portnoy are The Fatties: Fart Two.
在一些国家
In some countries,
对你放屁是种赞美
it's considered a compliment.
今夏释放
Letting loose this summer.
曾几何时  离经叛道就意味着被定罪
In a time where to be different was to be condemned,
而被定罪就意味着面临死亡
and to be condemned was to die,
而他  选择去质疑上帝…
one man chose to question his God...
由福克斯探照灯出品
From Fox Searchlight,
5次奥斯卡奖得主  柯克·拉扎勒斯
five-time Academy Award winner Kirk Lazarus
和MTV最佳亲吻奖得主  托比·马奎尔
and MTV Movie Award Best Kiss winner Tobey Maguire.
夺得北京电影节最让人梦寐以求的泣猴奖
Winner of the Beijing Film Festival's coveted Crying Monkey Award,
《恶魔小径》
Satan's Alley.
神父  我是个坏小孩  非常坏
I've been a bad, bad boy, Father.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视制作
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕 影视 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕制作：  cxj24394(TANK)  后期：  cxj24394(TANK)
1969年的冬天
In the winter of 1969,
美军的一支精英小队
an elite force of the U.S. Army
前往越南东南部执行绝密任务
was sent on a top-secret assignment in southeast Vietnam.
目标是救出  四叶·泰背中士
The objective, rescue Sergeant Four Leaf Tayback
地点是守卫森严的越军战俘集中营
from a heavily guarded NVA Prison Camp.
这可以称得上是自杀行动
The mission was considered to be near suicide.
派出去十个人  只有四人生还
Of the 10 men sent, four returned.
四人之中  三个人将经历写成了书
Of those four, three wrote books about what happened.
三人之中  两个人成功出版
Of those three, two were published.
两人之中  只有一人拿到了拍成电影的合同
Of those two, just one got a movie deal.
接下来的故事  讲的就是拍那部电影的人们
This is the story of the men who attempted to make that movie.
威士忌火蛇号  请求准备降落点
Whiskey Fire Old Snake requests an LZ prep
位置是甲丁2489  完毕
at Alpha-Delta-two-four-eight-niner, over.
福德号  这是领头飞机  右梯队从指定地点前往降落点  收到回话
Floyd, this is lead. Right echelon approach from RP to LZ, acknowledge.
福德号  斜眼号空降队  欢迎加入
Floyd, Wall-Eye airborne. Welcome aboard.
《热带惊雷》
好了  领头飞机过来了  给它点掩护
All right, lead's going in. Give her some cover.
从偏后方发射  重复  从偏后方发射
Delivery on five. I repeat, delivery on five.
这是03号  我在你正后方  别担心
This is Zero-Three. I'm on your six, don't worry.
粉笔3号受到攻击  向右开火  向右开火
Chalk-Three's taking fire. Guns right, guns right.
快把这破玩意降下来
Lay that shit down!
快点！
Come on!
来啊  你们这群粗野的异教徒！
Come on, you damn dirty heathens!
呼叫斜眼号  我是Z区投弹兵17号
Wall-Eye, Wall-Eye, this is Boomer One-Seven in the Zee!
请速派飞机过来投放炸弹  收到？
I need fast movers on my Yankee Smoke, copy?
呼叫投弹兵  斜眼收到  2甲4型蛇颈导弹
Boomer, this is Wall-Eye. I got two-Alpha-four
-准备完毕  -我的天哪！  我靠！
-snake and nape on the ready! -Oh, Jesus! Holy shit!
我靠！
Holy shit!
小子  你去拿话筒再要点火力过来
Get on that horn and get some firepower, boy!
我的天哪
Jesus Christ!
听着  你没破处的小崽儿
Listen, you cherry fuck,
快给我呼叫蛇颈导弹  来点轰炸！
you call in that snake and nape and get us some boom-boom now!
我也想去  可我他妈的正忙！
I'd do it myself but I'm kind of goddamn busy!
投弹兵请回话
I need an answer, Boomer!
斜眼斜眼！
Wall-Eye, Wall-Eye!
我收到了
I copy!
这他妈的是怎么回事？
What the fuck?
这是给布鲁克林报仇  王八蛋！
That's for Brooklyn, motherfucker!
我想我能把这塞回去
I think I can put it back in!
这个圣诞节是你们越军  最后一次当我的跟屁虫的机会了
This is the last Christmas I spend with Victor Charlie up my ass!
想来点吗？  吃我一棒吧！
Want some? Get some!
你  胖子  我没看见四叶的人影！
Hey, yo, Fats! I ain't seen Four Leaf!
别把他丢了！  那杂种的屁股上都纹了幸运符
Don't count him out! That bastard's got luck tattooed to his ass!
底特律  快点挪动你的卷毛屁股
Motown, get your Detroit jukebox Jheri curl ass
给我滚上这鸡屎飞机来  他妈的快点
in this chickenshit chop-chop! ASAFP!
四叶还在防线外面啊  中士！
Four Leaf is still outside the perimeter, Sarge!
不管那个单薄小屁妞了  咱们快走
Miss me with that cracker chump jive! We di di mau! We di di mau!
快点  卧倒  卧倒
Come on, get down, get down!
我眼前这是…啥吗东西？
What am I looking at? What is this?
快点  收摊走人了  升空起飞！
Come on, let's get, let's go! Come on, elevator up, up!
中士  那是四叶！
Sarge. It's Four Leaf.
不！
No!
挺住！
Survive!
掩护我  你们这帮硬不起来的笨蛋！
Cover me, you limp dick fuckups!
跟我藏猫猫？  看着你了！
Peek-a-boo! I see you!
坚持住  四叶！
Hold on, Four Leaf!
我靠！
Oh, shit!
注意我右边！
Watch my right!
来吧叶子  扭着走也要回去
Come on, Leaf, let's boogie!
不！
No!
-胖子！  -我靠啊！
-Fats! -Holy fuck!
别在他们头上转悠！  我靠
Take us over to those men! Shit!
瞧瞧你  敢拿手榴弹玩杂技
Look at you, man. Playing with grenades.
我身体冰凉  小林
I'm cold, Linc.
我的大腿没知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
也就蹭破了点皮
Ain't nothing but a thang.
握紧我的手
Hold my hands,
我有话
'cause I got something to
我有话要说
I got something to say.
乖乖！
Oh, boy.
等咱们回去了
When we get back to the world,
我要教你如何玩杂耍
I'm gonna finally teach you how to juggle.
我这一辈子一事无成
I ain't never been worth a nothing in this life,
…可我想跟你说
...but I want you to know something.
什么  哥们？
What, man?
你是我的…
You are my...
你是我兄弟
You are my brother.
你是我兄弟  你是…你是我…
You are my brother. You are my... You are my...
我是你的兄弟
I am your brother.
抱歉  咱们停下行吗？
I'm sorry. Could we cut?
-他说什么？  -达门  暂停行吗
-What's he saying? -Damien, can we cut?
-不行  不行…  -得了  你得明白？
-No. No, no, no, no, no... -All right, you know what?
再过2分钟  飞机就要过来弄个大爆炸场面了
We got the jets coming in, big explosion, two minutes.
继续拍下去
Still rolling.
我看算了  别拍了  暂停好吗？
You know what? No, not still rolling. Can we cut?
-咱们别拍了  -不  没停拍  快点！
-We're cutting. -No, we're not. Get out!
怎么不动了？  我屁股可疼死了！
Hey, what's going on? For real, my butt is hurting!
吊具卡到我屁股缝里了！
This harness is riding up my crack!
-达门  暂停了吗？  -没有  还在拍呢！
-Damien, are we cutting? -No! No! Still rolling!
考蛋先生！  停拍了吗？
Mr. Cockburn! Are we cutting, sir?
没停  没停！  还在拍摄！
No! No. I'm not cutting! We're still rolling!
达门  你什么指示？
Damien, what's the dealy, dude?
还要不要炸飞这排树？
Are we gonna blow this tree line or what?
他俩把忍了一年的蛋蛋们都拿来了
Tuk Tuk and Kim got the blue balls here.
一声令下  马上射飞！
I'm gonna let them squirt if we're a go!
-继续演  还在拍呢  -迪特  听得见我吧？
-Play it through. Still rolling! -Dieter, can he hear me?
笨蛋  这是C4炸药  快放回去  我要的是雷管
That's C-4, dipshit. Put that back. I said a detonator.
我需要些懂英语的家伙  真见鬼
I need some dudes up here who speak American, God damn it!
他在后面织他妈的毛衣呢
He's making a fucking sweater back here.
我正等着把神油抹在丛林的蛋蛋上呢
I'm trying to put Tiger Balm on this jungle's nuts.
Oh, shit. Alpa chino hot line.
What's up? What's up, baby?
妈的发生了什么事？
What the fuck is going on here?
大伙都安静点
Everyone, please shut up.
飞机马上就过来了  必须一次就拍摄成功！
The jets are coming in. We only have one chance at this!
宝贝  我数3下  1…2…呼吸
On three, baby. One, two, breathe.
帮个忙好吗？  我不想每次都倒计时
Look, do me a favor. I don't want to do a countdown before I do the scene.
-不倒计时？  -不倒计时
-No countdown? -No countdown.
-好吧  -那说“开拍”好了
-Okay. -Can we just do it off of "Action"?
算了…你跟着感觉走吧
Just... In your own time.
-好  -又不是要发射火箭
-Good... -I'm not a rocket ship, okay?
-得了  伙计们  -开拍！
-All right, dude. -And action!
不管想什么办法  靠！  别死！
Whatever floats your boat, baby. Fuck! Don't die!
给我瓶维他命水！
Erika, get me a VitaminWater!
知道么  达门  我先道歉
You know what it is, Damien? I'm sorry.
我不是要管他的事  可我哭了他也要哭？
Not to get into his thing, but if I'm crying, should Osiris be crying, too?
-都要哭…  -停拍还是接着哭？
-No, it's everyone cry... -We cutting or we crying?
-不不不  接着哭  -停拍得了！
-No, no, no, we're crying! -Just call it, man!
-柯克你要哭  奋力也哭  -谢谢
-Kirk, you can cry. Tugg, you can cry. -Thanks!
-两人都要哭…  -其实
-Everybody cry... -You know what?
-你看他的情绪也上来了  -确实
-You see how agitated he is now? -I know.
-我俩再挤出点酸水吧  -好  继续拍！
-Let's make lemonade. Let's go to work. -Okay. Still rolling!
这里是猎鹰一号  已经看见山脊  估计还有3公里
This is Falcon One. We have the ridge in sight, approximately two miles out.
迪特  飞机马上就要飞过山脊了
Dieter, these jets are about to crest this ridge line.
带着90多公斤炸药让你爽
They got about 200 pounds of shit your pants.
准备好了告诉我
I need to know if we're ready to go.
-你是我的… 我的  -我是你的…
-You're my... You're my... -I am your...
总算搞明白了  达门  是台词的问题
See, that's what I think it is, Damien. I think it's the line.
是吗？
Yeah?
我想四叶他…四叶？
I don't know if Four Leaf would say that... Four Leaf?
你手被炸飞了还会哭出来吗？
Were you crying when your hands blew up?
你看他摇头了  这样才符合…
No. See, he didn't. Yeah, I mean, just that's what...
现在要重写剧本了？
So now we in re-writes, right?
-你上哪去？  -那咱们重写好了
-Where you going? -Let's re-write it!
牛B主角不会哭  这么写好了
Action Jackson can't cry. That's what's going down.
柯克你别走了  我已经准备好拍这镜头了
You know what, Kirk? I'm ready to do the scene!
这个镜头？  这段是情感戏  你感情呢？
What scene? The scene is about emotionality. Where is it?
-那现在你们就改剧本吧！  -柯克…
-Now it's time to flip the script! -Kirk...
就算等到中国人过年了  这老兄也哭不出来
Be here till Chinese New Year waiting for my man to cry.
他们来了！
Here they come!
柯克 不 别再拖我的后腿了
Kirk, no. Stop tailgating me,
你这个糊状的茶包
you pasty tea bag.
我可以尿尿吗？
Can I make pee-pee?
飞机来了！
The planes are inbound!
我知道 妈的 拿到水果
I know. Oh, shit. Get the fruit.
天啦… 他妈的… 狗屎…
Jesus... fuck... shit... Cocksucking...
这是信号  快开始！
That's the signal! Go, go, go, go, go!
热带山雀...
Tropic tits...
他妈的踩屎的JB！
Goddamn shit-picking cock!
太漂亮了！
It's beautiful!
大地母亲刚被吓得尿了裤子！
Mother Nature just pissed her pantsuit!
爽啊！  爽啊！  靠！
-Sweet. -Oh, mama!
“丛林里面一团糟”
Bungle in the jungle.
《热带惊雷》在越南外景地传来更多坏消息
More bad news from the Vietnamese set of Tropic Thunder,
花了4百万美元把树林炸成焦土
where a $4 million explosion charred the Asian location
摄像机居然没有开拍
and the camera wasn't even rolling.
由急性子大亨雷斯·格罗斯曼投资
Financed by hotheaded mega-mogul Les Grossman,
才拍摄了5天  就有传言说电影会比原计划
the film is already rumored to be one month behind schedule
拖后1个月  要问原因？
just five days into shooting. The reason?
新手导演达门·考蛋是千夫所指
Fingers are pointed at rookie director Damien Cockburn,
知情人透露  他根本镇不住这些明星
who, insiders say, can't control a star-studded cast,
其中有超人气浮夸影星  肥胖大仙  杰夫·波特牛
including flatulent star of the popular Fatties franchise, Jeff Portnoy.
我告诉你们  很多人都瞧不起我
Let me tell you something. A lot of people are disrespecting me.
说这电影就是放屁  其实它是家庭片
They say that the movie's just about farts. It's about family,
去…你妈的！  你们可没我放屁的本事
and... you! You can't do what I do.
因为私藏各种毒品的罪名  他新近才被释放
Fresh from his most recent arrest for heroin, glue and crack possession,
波特牛现在可是最不靠谱
Portnoy was almost uninsurable.
还有代言PP香汗饮料的  说唱歌手阿尔帕·奇诺
Also in the mix is Booty Sweat-hocking hip-hop hyphenate Alpa Chino.
能来拍热带惊雷  我激动死了
I'm so excited, you know what I'm saying, about doing Tropic Thunder.
宝贝  别忘了喝PP香汗饮料！
Hey, drink Booty Sweat, baby. Drink Booty Sweat.
而演员当中真正重量级的…
But the real heavyweight on the set
是5次奥斯卡奖得主  柯克·拉扎勒斯
is five-time Academy Award winner Kirk Lazarus.
这个天才澳洲人  生活中一副坏小子形象
The brilliant Australian known for his bad boy antics off-screen
因为非常入戏而闻名
is famous for his total immersion into any role he portrays.
演员也一样
Well, being an actor is no different
和橄榄球  盖楼没区别
than being a rugby player or a construction worker,
虽说我善于
save for the fact that my tools
打动观众内心
are the mechanisms that trigger human emotion.
拉扎勒斯最近的手术广受争议
Lazarus underwent a controversial
他将皮肤染色
pigmentation alteration procedure in order to play
就为了演好黑人角色  林肯·奥西里斯
the platoon's African-American sergeant, Lincoln Osiris.
耶！
Yeah!
当然还有过气的
Trying to hold his own onscreen with Kirk
动作影星奋力·快男
is action juggernaut Tugg Speedman.
曾是全球收入最高的影星
Once the highest grossing star in the world,
不过《热天总动员》系列要降温了
lately his Scorcher films have lost their heat.
最近  快男对蒂拉敞开了心扉
Recently, Speedman opened up to Tyra.
你没有真正的家庭
You have no real family.
四十不惑了还在走着下坡路  没有孩子
You're on the wrong side of 40. You're childless and alone.
你一个朋友说
Somebody close to you said,
“再跌个跟头  这辈子就完了”
"One more flop and it's over."
有人说是我朋友？
Somebody said they were close to me?
他今年很不容易
It's been a tough year for Tugg.
先是无聊的友情喜剧《剧院伙计》
The disappointing buddy comedy Chitlin' & the Dude
然后头脑发热非要向演技派发展
was followed by an ill-advised venture into serious dramatic territory.
《笨蛋杰克》
Simple Jack,
讲述一个弱智农场工人  还能和动物对话
the story of a mentally impaired farmhand who can talk to animals,
成了票房毒药
was a box office disaster
许多评论家称之为“有史以来最糟糕的电影”
that many critics called, "One of the worst movies of all time."
我脑子不了了灵
I ain't got a good brain.
我觉得你的脑子很好用  杰克！
I think you've got a fine brain, Jack.
你日日让我开心
You make me happy.
可是快男能让观众们高高兴吗？
But now the question is, can Speedman make audiences happy
这最费钱的战争片
in what's being called the most expensive
-好像永远拍不出来了？  -瑞克·佩克找你
-war movie never made? -Rick Peck.
祝他好运吧
Wishing Tugg all the best on that one.
公子哥奋力  我是佩克  有时间和经纪人聊聊吗？
Rum-Tum-Tuggernauts, it's the Pecker. You got time for your agent?
-瑞克？  -是我  伙计
-Rick? -Hey, buddy,
猜猜我正看着谁？
guess who I'm staring at right now.
-什么？  -看着你的丑脸
-What? -I'm looking at your ugly mug
名利场杂志的封底
on the back cover of Vanity Fair magazine,
抱着个可爱的熊猫  给可爱村做广告
holding a cute, cuddly panda from Cutesville.
你真牛啊  跟摇滚明星似的
It is insane, bro. You are a rock star.
收到你的礼物篮了吗？
Hey, did you get the gift basket I sent?
他送的
From Rick.
是啊  很不错  谢谢你
Yeah. Yeah. It's cool, man. Thanks.
老兄  那是货真价实的卫星电话
All right, that is a real satellite phone, bro.
别随便就转手送人
Do not re-gift.
你看刚才的“直击好莱坞”节目了？
Hey. You see that Access Hollywood piece?
看了  好像在拿手枪抽盲童
Yeah, I did. It was like pistol-whipping a blind kid.
我不用安慰你  你本来就是大明星
I mean, I'm not gonna sugarcoat it, Tugg. You are a huge star, all right?
不过现在
But right now,
你就是球场上的那小孩
you're like that kid on the playground, you know,
头上长虱子  没人愿意和你玩
the one who has lice that none of the other kids want to play with?
-什么意思？  -你要洗心革面
-What do you mean? -I mean we gotta shave your head
就能回到滑梯上爽了
and get you back on the monkey bars, right?
啥？
What?
你那场哭戏怎么样
How did the crying scene go?
糟透了  拉扎勒斯也跟着哭
Horrible. Lazarus started crying.
鼻涕口水流我一身  剧本就没这么写…
Then he starts drooling and dribbling, and it wasn't even in the script...
别抱怨了！
Stop right there!
振奋起来  拖船
You gotta buck up here, Tuggboat.
谁在乎他是否更有才？
Who cares how much more talented he may be than you?
他要哭  你就哭得更狠！
If he cries, you cry harder, man.
小时候你的狗得过白血病吗？
Didn't your dog have, like, leukemia or something
想一想就哭出来了
when you were a kid? I mean, think of that.
搞定！  他们接好“替你录”了吗？
Boom! End of story. They hook up the TiVo yet?
-没有 -什么？
- Uh, no. - What?
他们有数字电视  我觉得够了
They have digital cable, but, I mean, it's okay.
不行  这可不行
No, no, no. Come on, man. It's not okay.
这可是大事儿  奋力！
It is not okay, Tugg!
你都不用向我解释为什么你需要“替你录”
And you don't need to explain to me why you need TiVo
或是纯净水啊  床单啊  食物帐篷之类的
or clean water, clean sheets, food, shelter.
在合同里帮你搞定这些是我份内的事
I mean, I fought for that in your contract.
对了  你收养小孩的事情怎么样了？
How's the adoption thing coming, buddy?
不怎么样
Not too great.
至少你还有得选
Well, at least you get to choose yours.
我是没得挑了
I'm stuck with mine.
你快回去工作吧  天才战士
Tell you what, get back to work, genius soldier.
“替你录”这事儿  我佩克帮你搞定！
The Pecker's on a TiVo mission for the Y-O-U.
练练掉眼泪  伙计
Work on those tears, my man.
好吧
All right. Yeah.
再跟我说一遍
Say it for me one time.
-你日日让我开心  -你日日让我开心
-You make me happy. -Make me happy.
-哥们没说的  -好的  再见
-I love you, buddy. -All right, bye.
紧急会议？  搞什么鬼？
Crisis meeting? What does that mean, exactly?
咱们有紧急危机了吗？
I mean, are we in a crisis?
他是电影公司的老大
He's the head of the studio.
不过摸不着咱们  离着1万6千公里远呢
He's reaching out. We're 10,000 miles away.
也就想来个小会面
He just wants a little face-time.
我知道  可你说他要开紧急会议  所以…
I know, it's just you said that he called it a crisis meeting. So...
他可是雷斯·格罗斯曼  爱用夸张的词儿
It's Les Grossman. He throws these words around.
“紧急”“爆发”“停机”“解雇”之类的
"Crisis," "explosion," "not rolling," "fired."
随便说说
These are just words.
爽啊！  爽！
Yeah! Yeah!
替我保密啊  他的摄影车刚把朱迪·丹奇给撞了
Keep a secret? A camera truck in London just plowed into Judi Dench.
相信我  他还有更操心的事儿
Trust me, he's got bigger problems.
他可能看得见我  但我看不见他
Look, he may be able to see me, but I can't see him.
-让开让开！  雷斯您好  -从我眼前滚开…
-Move! Move! Hello, Les! Hello! -Get your ass out of my...
-你踩我桌子了  -他能看得见我们？
-Your feet were on my desk. -Can he see us?
为什么我们没有…
I don't know why we don't have...
给他健怡可乐  雷斯  好了！
Get him a Diet Coke. Les! It's working!
是啊  不管你怎么搞的
Yeah, whatever you're doing right there. Hello, Les!
-你好  雷斯！  -你好
-Hello, Les! -Okay.
我们听你说话非常清楚
We got you loud and clear here, Les.
让我看看你们
I see you. I see you. I see you.
哪个欠揍的是  达门·考蛋？
Which one of you fuckfaces is Damien Cockburn?
是我  先生
That's me, sir.
咱们总算见着面了
It's good to finally meet you at last, get some face-time.
置景主任是谁？  你？  就你
And who here is the key grip? You? You.
对着导演的脸  给我狠狠地打
Hit that director in the face, really fucking hard.
抱歉  老兄
Sorry, man.
这是你的错  你个英国傻B
This is your fault, you limey fuck!
你把我的钱都给扔粪坑了
You shit the money-bed, my friend.
雷斯  我明白你很生气
Hey, Les, I understand if you're angry,
可这里的一群娘娘腔不好伺候
but I am dealing with a bunch of prima donnas!
那个小丑  奋力·快男  连哭都不会
Clowns! Tugg Speedman, he can't cry! He can't cry!
知道怎么对付演员吗？  只要他们一抱怨
You know how you handle an actor? They whine about anything,
把他们裤子扒了  照屁股就打
you pull down their pants and you spank their ass.
-狠狠地打  雷斯  -什么？
-You spank that ass, Les. -What?
把小孩打到哭成泪人
Spanking a child turns him into a little snot.
被打怕了就成男人了
Fear makes him a man.
我知道个地方  评价人的价值…
I know a place where a man's worth is measured...
是看脖子上的身份牌串着多少敌人的耳朵
in the ears hanging from his dog tags.
那才真正磨练人
The real deep shit.
想要拍好电影吗？
You wanna make this movie right?
就把这帮娘娘腔演员送到这样的地方
That's where you take your pansy-ass actors.
他又是谁？
Who is this guy?
雷斯  他就是四叶本人
Les, that's Four Leaf.
四叶·泰背中士  是我写的书
Sergeant Four Leaf Tayback. I wrote the book.
你是伟大的美国人  国家也欠你不少
You're a great American. This nation owes you a huge debt.
不过给我闭上臭嘴  让我干活！
Now shut the fuck up and let me do my job!
-听着  考蛋  -是
-Look, Cockburn. -Yes.
从现在开始  我的拳头可是离你屁眼不远了
From now on, my fist is gonna be so far up your shithole
以后不管想干什么
that every time you have a thought,
都得踮起脚尖做事  小心我带戒指的拳头
it's gonna have to tiptoe past my wedding ring.
管好你的演员  要不你就关门走人
Take control of your actors, or I will shut you down.
上瓶健怡可乐！
Diet Coke!
当羊群迷了路
When the herd loses its way,
牧羊人肯定要杀了乱带路的领头羊
the shepherd must kill the bull that leads them astray.
-四叶？  -过来吧  别怕
-Four Leaf? -Come on over. It's okay.
-坐下  -好
-Sit down. -Yes.
-你不喜欢住旅馆？  -睡床上会做噩梦
-So, you don't like the hotel? -Beds give me nightmares.
我看你这状态  就好比找不到自己的熊皮
I'm guessing right about now you couldn't find a Dixie coonskin
也没有俄亥俄的小姐拉着你的小弟弟领路一样
with an Ohio hooker holding your prick and showing you the way.
啥？
What?
我把故事交到了你这英国佬手上
I put my story in your limp Brit hands,
你不能让我失望
and you are not going to fail me.
你以为今天开会我是在虚张声势？
You think I was just blowing my own bagpipe in that meeting?
你得把演员扔到困境里面
You must put those boys in the shit.
什么？  我没听明白
What? I don't understand.
-你到底想不想拍好电影？  -想啊
-You wanna make your movie or not? -Yes, I do.
那好  把那些小摄像机都拿出来
All right, you get some of those little video type cameras.
咱们把它们藏到树底下  对着不同的角度
We take them out there, and we put them in the trees in different angles.
然后把你手里所有的炸药地雷什么的
Then you give me and that pyromaniac Cody
都交给我和那个纵火狂科迪
all the smoke bombs, charges, explosives, detonators you got.
然后咱们就把孩子们扔到野地里
Then we take those boys up there,
我和科迪把这林子点着了
me and Cody, we could light up that fucking jungle,
那些蔫了吧唧的演员们会屁滚尿流
so those lily-dick actors would be shitting their pants
哭着喊妈妈
and screaming for their mammies.
为了能回家  就算呆在运尸袋里也愿意
They'd be begging for a body bag if it means a ride home.
我可以这么干
I could do it.
能拍成游击队的风格  心狠手辣那种
I could shoot the whole thing guerrilla style. Gritty, dirty.
不能让闲人或马屁经纪人帮他们
Get them away from their helpers and ass-licking assistants.
你得来真格的！
Put them in the real shit.
-真格的  -要真的害怕！
-Real shit. -With real fear in their eyes!
真正的恐惧和情感！  四叶  太对了！
Real fear, real emotion! Yes, Four Leaf, yes!
-就这么干！  -就这么干！
-Yes! Yes! -Yes! Yes!
让他们从舒服窝里滚出来！
Take them off the fucking grid!
你们不再是电影里的演员了
You are no longer actors in a movie!
你们是直升飞机里的5个爷们！
You are five men in a helicopter!
外加3个爷们！
With three other men!
我们要去多久？
How long are we gonna be gone, anyways?
我把维生素片忘在旅馆了
'Cause I left most of my vitamins back at the hotel.
-别费心思了  你个苍蝇蛆  -他说得对  苍蝇蛆
-Save your breath, maggots! -That's right, maggots!
下去  下去！  从直升飞机里下去！
Go, go, go! Get out of the chopper!
快点  苍蝇蛆  动作快点！
Move it, maggots, move! Move, grunts, move your ass!
快点  你们这些小虫子
Get out, you wriggly worms!
-太高了  -快点
-It's up too high! -Move, move, move!
地狱里见吧！
See you in hell!
真是胡搞  怎么也要给我的经纪人打个电话
This is bullshit! I gotta at least call my fucking assistant.
我靠！  天哪！  老兄！
Fucking! Jesus! Dude!
你们现在是在越共军队的老巢里面
You're sitting on a nest of hostile enemy V.C.
祝贺你  胖子  你这么嚷嚷会把大家都害死
Congratulations, Fats. You just got us all killed.
还有人想暴露咱们的位置吗？
Anybody else care to give away our position to Charlie?
手机！
Cell phones!
你这是干嘛  达门？
What the hell, Damien?
1969年可是没手机的  我这一身才配套
Weren't no cell phones in '69, man. I'm head-to-toe legitimate.
先生们  有好消息也有坏消息
Gentlemen, I've got good news and bad news.
坏消息是电影公司想要让咱们走人
The studio wants to shut us down. That's the bad news.
好消息呢
And the good news.
想要挽救这部电影  大家就齐心协力
If you wanna save this movie, you will become a unit.
你们的任务是向北穿过当考河
Your objective is to head north to the D'ang Kwook River
解放战俘营
and liberate the POW camp,
四叶会被关在那里
at which point Four Leaf will get himself captured,
你们要去那里营救
at which point you will rescue him,
等拍完了就上直升机回家
at which point we will chopper you home!
靠啊
Damn.
四叶  既然你是头儿
Four Leaf, since you're the staff sergeant,
地图就给你了  这是场景列表
there's the map, this is the scene list.
你觉得能搞定吧？
Think you can handle it?
我们在整个死亡峡谷都隐藏好了摄像头
We have rigged this entire valley of death with hidden cameras.
我也会从你们看不到的地方拍摄
And I will be shooting as well, from unseen vantage points,
这样就能捕捉到所有精彩瞬间
so that every glorious moment is captured on film.
相信我  先生们  一定会十分精彩
And believe me, gentlemen, it will be glorious.
要是来真的  拍得也会更真实
If it looks real, chances are it probably is.
你们想要成为好演员
You wanted to be actors.
你们想要塑造角色
You wanted to occupy the skin of another human being.
那先变成一个恐惧下咆哮的美军士兵吧
Well, get ready to occupy the skin of a terrified U.S. Infantry grunt,
生命受威胁  从死神的屁股下侥幸逃脱
surrounded by death, crawling up Satan's bottom.
会有伏击和敌军火力  和属于你们自己的越南体验
There'll be ambushes, enemy fire, your own little personal slice of 'Nam.
这个无线电话只能和直升机通讯
This radio goes to the chopper and the chopper only.
直升机就是上帝  我就是你们的耶稣  上帝之子
The chopper is God, and I am Jesus Christ, his son.
你们就是我挑选的信徒
You are my chosen disciples.
不拍完了谁也别想回去
And no one gets to go home till we get the shots.
拿出你们士兵打仗的样子来
Put on your war faces, gentlemen.
让咱们拍成这部最伟大的战争电影！
Now, let's go and make the greatest war movie ever!
-好！  -好啊！
-Yeah! -All right!
耶！  耶！
Yeah! Yeah!
老大  我们在北部听到了爆炸的声音
-快跟着它  -收到
走吧
考蛋  装得挺像嘛
Not bad, Cockburn!
真不错
Not bad.
不管你在哪！
Wherever you are!
他去哪儿了？  看着好像天女散花了
Wherever he is? Looks like he's all over the place.
就是这个
Here we go.
一定是老式的法国地雷
Must be an old French mine.
原来的中印殖民地时留下的  树林里肯定到处都有
It's a remnant from colonial Indo-China. This jungle must be full of them.
还不明白吗？  这是要让大家摸不着头脑
Don't you get it? He's messing with our heads.
所以他才说什么上帝
That's what all that playing God stuff was about.
他是想让咱们演得更好  拯救这部电影
He's trying to get us to act good, save the movie.
他才不是上帝  上帝已经惩罚他了
He ain't playing God. He's being judged by him.
这些场景就是目标  咱们去完成任务
That's our objective. Complete the mission.
我们遇到了火力强大的美军
是D.E.A吗？
可能
柯克  无意冒犯你  我知道你是这里最大牌儿的演员
No offense, Kirk, I know you're the big fancy actor here,
不过我可是出演过很多视觉特效大片
but I've done a lot more effects-driven event films than you. Okay?
我觉得还是认出来
And I think I can spot
一个人头道具的
a prop head when I see one.
噢  老天
Oh, Jesus.
是玉米糖浆  伙计们  玉米糖浆和乳胶
It's corn syrup, guys. Corn syrup and latex.
暖和的  带着血味儿的玉米糖浆
Warm, blood-flavored corn syrup.
天哪
Oh, God.
电影特效  欢迎来到电影工厂
Smoke and mirrors, guys. Welcome to the movie factory.
书上的老把戏了
Oldest trick in the book.
他总算说点有用的了
He getting down now.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
看看我！
Whoa, look at me!
“你们要拍完每个镜头”
You're going to get the shots,
“作为导演我会确保这一点”
and I'm going to make sure because I'm the director.
“我来自伦敦  导演过歌剧”
I'm from London. I direct plays.
达门！  我们已经变身军人了啊！
Hey, Damien! We got our war faces on!
他们根本不怕死
把他们抓住  不管死活
看啊  我是大卫·贝克汉姆！
Look, I'm Dave Beckham.
我们今天要在他们身上放把火吧？
So, we gotta light these boys up today, huh?
让这些年轻人长点见识
Blow some sense into these young men.
你别认为我说这话很怪…
Hey, I don't want to come off as weird or anything,
我可能算得上你的头号粉丝了
but I might be your biggest fan. Yeah.
《热带惊雷》就好比是我的《麦田守望者》
Tropic Thunder. Kind of like my Catcher in the Rye.
虽然我本身没参过军
Yeah, I've never been in the military, per se,
可我也为了职责丢过些身体零件
but I have lost an appendage in the line of duty.
《为黛茜小姐开车》里的马车试镜弄的
Driving Miss Daisy, first studio gig.
是啊
Yeah.
你这随身装备挺酷啊  叫什么？
It's a pretty cool sidearm you got there. What is it?
我不知道它叫什么
I don't know what it's called.
我只知道它夺人性命时发出的声音
I just know the sound it makes when it takes a man's life.
好吧
Okay.
达门  我们准备好了
Damien, we're go for explosion.
只要你下令  我就点火让他们爽歪歪
Ready to kick the tires and light the fires on your say-so.
达门  我们准备好引爆了
Damien, we're go for explosion.
收到了吗？
Do you copy?
我都要忍不住了  已经准备好炸个狠的
I got an itchy trigger finger here, and I'm ready to blow some shit up.
现在总该信了吧？  可以开拍了吧？
All right, you happy now? Can we do the scene?
还是要给一个正式通知才行？  来吧  咱们走
Or do you need a formal invitation? Come on, let's go!
走吧  好了
Here. Okay.
“第12幕  白天  林中空地  外景  埋伏”
"Scene 12, exterior, jungle clearing, day, ambush.
“四叶观察到了树林里的动静”
"Four Leaf notices movement in the brush.
“看到一个游击小队在林中移动”
"A dozen guerrilla fighters can be seen moving in the tree line.
“一处地雷发生爆炸” 然后你
"Somewhere a mine explodes." And you.
“我有不祥的预感”
"I got a bad feeling on this one."
-我是有  -不  那句是你的台词
-Yeah. -No, that's your line.
-我有… 现在就说？  -是啊  但是带上点恐惧
-I got... Now? -Yeah, but scared. Like, scared.
-“我有不详的预感”  -等等  什么语气？
-"I got a bad feeling on this one." -Dude, wait, like how?
“我有不详的预感”
"I got a bad feeling on this one."
-好的  -开拍  快点
-Okay. -Action. Go, come on.
我有不详的预感  胖子
I got a bad feeling on this one there, Fats.
要是出了这狗屁山谷  屁股还没炸烂
Our asses don't get fragged in this bullshit valley,
我回去第一件事  就是花两块钱
first thing I'm doing is paying my two bucks
去看布鲁克林以童男之身和一个…
so I can watch Brooklyn bust his cherry
越南小妞乱搞
on a sweet little mama-san's dinky dau poontang.
得了  还没搞成就被蒙面绑走了
Shit, Brooklyn be bagged and tagged before he get any cooch.
他死了估计还是个小处男
He die, he probably die a coochless motherfucker.
闭嘴  底特律
Zip it, Motown.
渴死我了
Man, I'm thirsty.
不如喝点我在越南岘港带来的PP香汗饮料
Might as well have some of this Booty Sweat I got back in Danang.
你们这群混蛋  那狗娘养的没命了！
Yo, asshole! This motherfucker's dead!
没有什么上帝耶稣的胡扯了
Ain't no Criss Angel Mindfreak,
这也没什么大卫的脱身魔术
David Blaine trapdoor horseshit jumping off here!
你是跟我们一块走  还是浪费下个镜头？
Hey! You wanna get on the train here, or do you wanna ruin another take?
浪费个屁！  早没有人摄影了！
There ain't no goddamn takes, ain't no goddamn motion picture!
-你确信？  -是啊
-You sure? -Yeah.
-真的？  -非常肯定
-Yeah? -For certain, man.
那你怎么还沉浸在角色里？
Then why are you still in character?
我自己明白  没必要告诉你
I know, but I don't have to tell you.
你不明白
You don't know.
直到录完DVD评论音轨我才走出角色
Man, I don't drop character till I done a DVD commentary.
这回满意了吧？  大家都没走位呢！
You happy now? We're out of position for the effects!
卧倒  傻瓜
Get down, fool!
没人读剧本吗？  这是偷袭一幕
Didn't anyone read the script? This is the ambush!
-子弹还挺真的  -是啊  好好利用这机会
-This feels pretty real! -Exactly! Let's use it.
耶！
Yeah!
吃我的子弹！
Eat lead!
他们开枪射击打得跟疯狗一样
They're busting caps like a motherfucker down there.
这回可玩疯了  我说咱们给他们加点更刺激的“料”
This is FUBAR. I say we juice them.
-你觉得呢？  -那就给他们“加料”
-What do you think? -Juice them.
越军去死吧！
Fuck you, Charlie!
这可是强力奶头
Big-ass titties!
炸弹  快跑！
看看啊
Look at that, huh?
暂停！
And cut!
预告片就这么拍出来了
That's the trailer right there.
爽！
Yeah!
-现在咱们怎么办？  -是啊
-What do we do now? -Yeah.
往北走  导演让咱们朝北走
North. Man said to head north.
-看见我开枪的样子了吗？  -这才是真正的表演
-Did you see me shooting? -That's how we do. Good work, baby.
说得没错
I believed it.
前往当考河
D'ang Kwook River.
我打赌他还会安排些这样的战斗
I'm betting he's got more of these battles
沿路遭到越共偷袭什么的
and Viet Congs rigged for us along the way.
奥西里斯中士  集合士兵  整装待发
Sergeant Osiris, get your men. Load and lock.
我可是来真的
Real, baby, I'm real.
咱们出发  还要走几公里的路呢
Let's go! We got a lot of klicks to cover!
扛起枪来  一字小队前进！
Hump it up, gentlemen! Single formation.
别磨蹭了
Don't dawdle now!
大棒  大棒  我是胖脸  刚才场景拍得怎么样？
D-Rod, D-Rod, this is Puddingface. How are we coming on that hotplate?
肯定出了什么问题  咱们最好下去看看
Something's up. I think we better drag ass back there.
确保这回达门别忘了怎么用对讲机
Make sure Damien ain't forgot how to use his talkbox again.
宝贝儿  让我尝尝
Yeah, baby, come on. Just a little taste.
-你在干嘛  杰夫？  -他妈的什么都没干！
-What are you doing, Jeff? -Fucking... Nothing, man!
-我在吃豆粒软糖  -我也爱吃  给我点行吗
-I'm eating jellybeans. -Wow, I love jellybeans. Can I please...
不行  屁都不给你吃
No, you can't have any fucking jellybeans.
都是我的
They're mine.
你以为只有你不吃豆粒软糖
You think you're the only one who gets sick
就浑身难受吗？
when he doesn't have his jellybeans?
别贪得无厌  靠
Boundaries, man. Fuck.
其实我刚才不是非要揭你短
Hey. I didn't mean to show you up back there.
我只是觉得咱们得给其他人树立榜样
It's just, I feel like we really need to set the example for the other guys.
这次会很辛苦
It's gonna be tough,
不过我觉得达门拍到了一些好镜头
but I think Damien's gonna get some great shit out of us.
真希望演杰克的时候  导演是他
Just wish I had a director like this on Jack.
演杰克？  什么杰克？
On Jack. What? Jack? What you talking about?
-《笨蛋杰克》  -噢  是那个
-Simple Jack. -Oh, yeah.
笨蛋杰克  尽全力演出的吧？
Simple Jack, yeah. You went all out on that one, huh?
很不错  真是惊世骇俗
You did. Really swung for the fences, huh?
多谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thanks. Yeah.
其实演杰克挺费心的
Yeah, it was an intense experience, you know.
我下了很多功夫
I just did the work.
花时间和很多弱智的人在一起  观察他们
Watched a lot of retarded people. Spent time with them. Observed them.
观察他们是怎么弱智的
Watched all the retarded stuff they did.
其实我一直觉得
Then again, I always found mere observation
仅仅观察还是得来太肤浅
in and of itself is a tad rudimentary.
有时候  我们得深入挖掘人物的情感矛盾
Sometimes, we gotta dig deeper to mine the true emotional pay dirt.
发掘出痛苦的源头  亲身实践它
Thus, we can diagram the source of the pain and then live it, you know.
是啊  对  亲身实践
Yeah, yeah, live it. Yeah, exactly.
你知道么  我演杰克那阵子
You know, there were times when I was doing Jack
有时候我觉得自己是真傻了
that I actually felt retarded,
-是真的傻了  -我靠
-like really retarded. -Oh, yeah.
我不得不以奇怪的方式让自己更豁达
In a weird way, I had to sort of just free myself up
告诉自己当弱智或者傻子也没什么
to believe that it was okay to be stupid or dumb.
-当个低能儿？  -是啊
-To be a moron. -Yeah.
-大脑低能的人  -对  低能儿
-To be moronical. -Exactly, to be a moron.
-痴呆  -没错
-An imbecile. -Yeah.
就像有史以来最最傻B的白痴？
Like the dumbest motherfucker that ever lived.
当我扮演角色时
When I was playing the character.
-当你进入角色时  -是啊  我是杰克的时候
-When you was the character. -Yeah, as Jack, definitely.
杰克  蠢蛋杰克
Jack, stupid ass Jack.
等拍摄要结束了  我就想
by the end of the whole thing, I was like,
“我入戏太久了  怎么回到原来的生活？”
"Wait a minute, I flushed so much out, how am I gonna jumpstart it up again?"
-感觉有点那个  是吧？  -是啊
-It's just like... Right? -Yeah.
你连在澡盆里放屁  笑掉大牙都演了
You was farting in bathtubs and laughing your ass off.
是的 我的意思是 这真的是一个…
Yeah. I mean, it was really quite a...
这太疯狂了
It was crazy.
好像神灵附体一样  那可是高深技术  那是艺术
It's like working with mercury. It's high science, man. It's an art form.
-是啊  -你是艺术家
-Yeah. -You an artist.
-咱们就是在艺术创作  -没错
-That's what we do, right? Yeah. -Yeah.
我为你脱帽致敬
Hats off for going there,
尤其是知道奥斯卡怎么评奖之后  你还能这样
especially knowing how the Academy is about that shit.
-什么怎么评奖？  -你真不知道？  没装傻？
-About what? -You're serious? You don't know?
大伙都明白不能演彻底的白痴
Everybody knows you never go full retard.
-你是什么意思？  -不信咱们数数看
-What do you mean? -Check it out.
《雨人》里的霍夫曼长相很傻  表现很傻  但不是真傻
Dustin Hoffman, Rain Man, looked retarded, act retarded, not retarded.
他会数牙签  玩牌时作弊  顶多算自闭症  可不是白痴
Count toothpicks, cheat at cards. Autistic, sure. Not retarded.
《阿甘正传》里的汤姆·汉克斯
Then you got Tom Hanks, Forrest Gump.
脑筋慢  可能还有点笨  腿上戴着矫正支架
Slow, yes, retarded, maybe, braces on his legs.
可他能赢得尼克松的喜爱  还能赢得乒乓球比赛
But he charmed the pants off Nixon, and he won a Ping-Pong competition.
那就不是真傻
That ain't retarded.
1979年《富贵逼人来》里的塞勒  有点幼稚  但不是傻子
And he was a goddamn war hero. You know any retarded war heroes?
可你演的是大傻子
You went full retard, man.
千万别演个大傻子
Never go full retard.
你还不信？  自己去问01年《不一样的爸爸》的西恩·潘
You don't buy that? Ask Sean Penn, 2001, I Am Sam.
想起来了？  演成大傻子了  什么奖都没得
Remember? Went full retard? Went home empty-handed.
老天啊  真是见鬼了！
Oh, my God! Holy shit!
你个臭狗屎杀了导演
Good job, turd. You killed the director.
不  这不可能
No, that's impossible, man.
我沿着树林线布置的  可他死这儿了
I rigged the whole tree line, and this is here.
-他肯定忘了自己的记号了  -忘了？
-He must have missed his mark. -Missed his mark?
是啊  可这不怨我
Yeah, this isn't me.
得了  找个袋子把他包起来回旅馆吧
Come on, let's bag and tag the bastard and get back to the hotel.
-你算完了  呆瓜！  -咱俩都完了
-You're in a world of hurt, dumbo! -We're in a world of hurt!
-就你自己  -不能只怨我
-You're in trouble. -This isn't just on me!
-咱们都…  咱们都有份儿  -胡说
-We're in a... We're together on this. -Bullshit.
你就想这么溜走？
You're just gonna run away. You're gonna leave.
还说什么“不扔下一个弟兄”
What happened to, "No man left behind," okay?
你等等  听我说
Just wait, just wait! Listen! Listen, okay?
-我才不听  -我跟你说真的
-I don't wanna hear it. -Let me just be real with you, all right?
拍《辣妈辣妹》时我差点弄瞎了杰米·李·柯蒂斯
I almost blinded Jamie Lee Curtis on Freaky Friday, okay?
再有这事儿  我就彻底完了
This shit will fucking ruin me!
-放开我  你这可怜虫  -我才不是
-Just get off me! You're pathetic. -No, I'm not.
-放开我  -你不能回去！
-Get off me! -You are not going back!
-这他妈的是怎么回事？  -等一下
-What the fuck? -Now wait a minute.
恨死拍电影了
I fucking hate movies.
这是在胡搞  我可不想拍这种烂片
This is bullshit. I don't wanna be in this shitty movie.
不行  把我的豆粒软糖还给我！  不！
No! That's my jellybeans! No!
小子  抓住蝙蝠！  求你了！  靠！
Kid, grab the bat! Please! Shit!
-算了  我这儿有高潮坚果棒  -你去死吧！  它在那
-Yo, man, I got a Bust-A-Nut. -You go to hell! There he is.
我靠啊  跑哪去了？
God damn it! Okay. Where'd he go?
你个小烂屎  回头把你翅膀扯下来
You little piece of shit! I'm gonna fucking rip your wings off!
山德祺  别动  小声保密
Sanducci. Hold up, man, keep it on the down-low.
我不是来尿尿  而是想跟你聊聊
I don't really gotta piss. I'm trying to talk at you, man.
诱饵  我需要诱饵
Bait, I need bait.
你参加过新兵训练营吧？  会看地图吧？
You went to boot camp, right? You can read a map?
应该能行
Yeah, I think so.
我知道快男让大家深信我们跑到这鬼地方
I know Speedman got everyone convinced we out here
在拍能上Youtube的《人猿星球》或什么鬼东西  可我不信
making Planet of the Apes on YouTube or some shit, but I don't buy it.
你想踩着真地雷吗？  想死吗？
You wanna step on a real landmine? You wanna die?
想被狗日的真地打死？
You wanna get shot by a real motherfucker?
-向前看  伙计  -我当然不想
-Keep looking ahead, man. -No, of course not.
我要是把地图交给你  能够信任你吗
If I can put that map in your hands, can I count on you?
-行  我想可以  -好小伙  那我走了
-Well, yeah, I guess you can. -Dynamite. I'm out.
闻起来好像腊肠
That smelled just like bologna for some reason.
他妈的就没人帮我捉住这鬼东西吗？
Is anyone gonna fucking help me get this fucking thing?
大白天的怎么会有蝙蝠
Why are they even out in the daytime?
跟你说实话  我不想尿尿  只是跟你谈谈
I'm gonna level with you, bro. I don't need to pee. I need to talk to you.
拉扎勒斯他想要破坏电影
Lazarus is gonna torpedo the movie.
他自己的角色都演不好
He's way out on a limb with this character,
我想他越来越胆小了
and I think he's getting cold feet.
我需要你站在我这边  凯尔
I need you on my side, Kyle.
我叫凯文
It's Kevin.
好  那我能相信你吗
Good. Can I count on you?
可以  你要是想让我帮你看地图也行
If you want I could give the map a look-see.
-我会看地图  -好的
-I'll handle the map. -Okay.
你按照计划走  咱们肯定能把电影拍完
You stick with the program, we get this movie in the can,
估计你还能得个“青少年选择奖”
I'm thinking there could be a Teen Choice Award in it for you.
你有这潜力  孩子们会追捧你  就这么回事
You have that potential. They'll slime you, the whole deal.
-听起来不错  -那就好
-Yeah, that's wicked. -Good.
在那儿呢  你死定了
There it is! Yeah, now you're dead!
你吃药吃多了
You O.D.'d!
你等等  杰夫
Hold up now, Jeff.
真他妈该死！
Fucking hell!
你搞什么鬼？  那是个蝙蝠
What the hell, Jeff? That's a bat, man!
我没有豆粒软糖了
I don't have any more jellybeans.
在那儿降落！
You land there!
看看这废墟
Wow. Look at these ruins.
-我们到底在哪？  -当考河
-Where the hell are we? -D'ang Kwook River.
真的？  你怎么知道的？  你确定？
That so? How do you know that? How you sure?
伙计们  检验办法只有一个  咱们走
Only one way to find out, dude. Let's go.
我有点不舒服  说真的  我皮肤特别疼
Yeah. I'm not feeling so good right now. Seriously, my skin hurts!
别老在雅座里呆着了  下水吧  小妞们
Enough from the peanut gallery! Into the water, ladies!
等等  让我看一眼地图  很快的
No, man. Let me take a look at that map right quick.
你们怎么都惦记着地图啊？
Why is everybody all obsessed with the map?
因为我们厌倦了像个傻瓜似地跟在你后面
'Cause we're tired of being your trail donkeys!
好像你是什么真人GPS似的
Acting like you some one-man GPS!
我靠！  咱们迷路了！  他妈的彻底迷路了！
God damn it! We lost! We fucking super lost, man!
麦考斯基  告诉他几点了
Tell him, McClusky. Tell him what time it is.
真没想到你们这些人怎么这样
I don't believe you people.
你说“你们黑人”什么意思？
What do you mean "you people"?
What do you mean, "you people"?
奋力  其实想说的是…
I think what Tugg means is...
别解释  你看他眼睛
No, look at his eyes, man.
-我是说你们这些演员…  -你看他那邪恶的白色水泡眼
-...you people, you actors. You people... -Look at them beady, white devil eyes.
我必须得回旅馆  真的！
I gotta get back to the hotel, for real!
-没戏！  -闭嘴！
-Hell, no! -Silence!
都给我冷静！  行吧？
Chill! All right? Just chill it.
现在  去找那些越共们
Now, let's go get those Viet Congs.
-“越共”！  -什么？
-"Viet Cong"! -What?
是“越共” 不是“越共们” 越共已经指多人了
It's "Viet Cong." There's no "S." It's already plural.
好比不能说“中国人们”
You wouldn't say "Chineses."
行了  别跟咱们的领导抬杠了！
All right, that's enough of this insubordination!
咱们核心垮了  大家也活不了
If the machine breaks down, we break down.
你知道在《第一滴血1》里  兰博还有点肥肉
Hey, man, you know how in Rambo I, he was big but a little puffy
可到了《第一滴血2》  他全是肌肉块了？
and then Rambo II, he got all shredded up?
-知道  -你现在就那样
-Yeah. -That's kind of how you look right now.
-真的？  -不是指《第一滴血1》而是指《第一滴血2》
-Yeah? -Not Rambo I but II.
-真的吗？  -对  愤怒兰博那样
-Really? -Yeah, when he was cut up.
我不是…我当然想变成那样  可…
I'm not that... I mean, that's what I'm going for, but you know...
得了  你可比切成条的色拉还有型
Come on, dude. You more shredded than a julienne salad, man.
-谢谢  -你有什么秘诀吗？
-Thanks. -What's the secret, dude?
-是食谱  我在控制饮食  -真的？
-It's a diet. I'm just dieting. -Really?
其实我也想长点肌肉  可不容易
'Cause I'm trying to come up a little, but it's just... It's tough.
-你看着挺好的  -来点建议？
-You look good. -Any tips?
-什么？  -给我点建议？
-What? -Any tips, you got?
比方说  菠萝之类的…
There's, like, the pineapple...
把破地图给我！  去你妈的
-Give me that goddamn map! Fuck you! -Hey!
-嗨  -现在好了！
-Hey! -All right, now!
怎么说  斯考斯基？  我们究竟在哪儿？
What it is, Sikorski? Tell us where we really at.
胡扯个屁！  你这是傻子白费劲
That's fucking bullshit! It's a chump move.
我们只想听听不同意见  假博士
We just getting a second opinion, doc.
咱们走错了
We're going the wrong way!
-靠！  -混蛋
-Damn! -Son of a bitch.
天哪  我想咱们本来应该这么走
God! I think we were supposed to be doing this,
结果却这么走了
and instead we did this.
我靠！  我靠！  我靠靠靠！
Shit, shit, shit, shitty shit, shit!
你觉得咱们还能回到降落的地方吗？
Think you can get us back to that drop zone, boy?
这可糟了
This is not cool!
应该能行
Maybe.
这么做太愚蠢了！
This is insane!
你们真要放弃这部电影了？
Are you really going to abandon this movie?
咱们应该亲密团结啊！
We're supposed to be a unit!
亲我老二去吧！
Suck my unit!
算了  好吧
All right, fine.
-我自己拍完  -你爱咋地就咋地
-I'll finish it by myself. -You go be all you can be, man.
奋力  你根本不知道你这是要去哪儿
Tugg, you have no idea where you're going!
当然知道
Yes, I do!
我要去拍“热带雨林外景  傍晚”
I'm going to, "Exterior, rain forest, dusk.
“镜头忽然对准四叶  他正穿过骇人丛林独行着”
"Smash cut to Four Leaf, who treks alone through a frightening jungle."
亲亲这情节去吧  柯克！
Suck on that unit, Kirk!
来吧  伙计们  咱们回家吧
Come on, men. Let's get home.
你好  螳螂先生  你真漂亮
Hello, Mr. Mantis. You're beautiful.
你如果回想起那阵子
Now, if you recall that whole hullabaloo
好莱坞分成两派
where Hollywood was split into schisms,
一些公司吵吵着支持蓝光DVD  另一些支持HD  DVD
some studios backing Blu-ray Disc, others backing HD DVD.
人们都以为最后取决于…
People thought it would come down to
像素速率或刷新率  其实这两个概念没什么区别
pixel rate or refresh rate, and they're pretty much the same.
不过真正起作用的  是做游戏和拍A片的怎么选
What it came down to was a combination of gamers and porn.
得A片者得天下
Now, whichever format porno backs
A片支持的才是牛B的
is usually the one that becomes the most successful.
再比如索尼的Playstation  3也支持蓝光
But, you know, Sony, every PlayStation 3 has a Blu-ray in it.
这么半天你在跟我说话啊？
You talking to me this whole time?
谁愿意听都行
I was talking to whoever was listening to me.
天哪
Jesus Christ, man!
PP香汗饮料
Booty Sweat.
天哪
Oh, God!
好冷！  冷死了  他妈的冷死我了
It's cold! It's freezing. I'm fucking cold.
我把防弹衣给你？
You want my flak jacket?
你有病啊？  我烧开水似的在冒汗！  洗桑拿一样
What, are you insane? It's boiling! It's like a sweat lodge out here!
发牢骚小声点  放屁·亚当先生
Keep the volume down on that bitching, Flatch Adams.
我想拉上10斤屎
I gotta take a fucking 12-pound shit!
-怎么样？  咱们顺利吗？  -很顺利
-How we doing? We making good time? -We're making good time,
不过在天黑之前不可能翻过那座山
but there's no way we make it over that ridge before sundown.
好吧伙计们  咱们扎营  休息！
All right, fellas, we're gonna make camp, rest up!
-天哪  -估计我能请大家吃晚饭
-Oh, God. -Y'all might be in for a treat.
想当年  战争爆发以前
You know, back before the war broked out,
在圣安东尼奥城  我是法式调味师
I was a saucier in San Antone.
我估计能找点野菜
I bet I could collar up some of them greens.
从庄稼里现磨面做点小龙虾面条  哥们儿！
Yeah, noodle some crawfish out the paddy, yo.
再拿点野果做点心  你们听见了？  他妈的爽！
And maybe some crab apples for dessert, now, you hear? Hell, yeah!
他妈的爽！
Hell, yeah!
黑人就这么说话  我们都这么说话  操
That's how we all talk. We all talk like this, suh! Yes, suh.
“弄点小龙虾和排骨  我爽”
Yeah, get some crawfish and some ribs.
你是澳大利亚人！  说自己人的话！  抢钱袋鼠！
You're Australian! Be Australian! Excuse me, Kangaroo Jack.
想起做饭我就沉不住气
I get excited about my foods, man.
（这是电视剧《星际旅行》Star  Trek  而他要拍的场景正好是丛林旅行Jungle  Trek）
去死吧！
Die!
不！
No!
伙计！  这究竟是怎么回事？  咱们在哪？
Dude, dude, what the hell is going on here? Where are we?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我从没离开过美国
I've never been outside the States.
等等  说啥？  你他妈的逗我玩呢？
Wait, what? Are you fucking kidding me?
你自己胡编的整个剧本？
Did you make this whole goddamn thing up?
伙计  你是不是都没当过兵？
Dude, were you even in the fucking service?
我当过  海岸巡逻队
Yes. Of course. Coast Guard.
-海岸巡逻队  -环境卫生部
-Coast Guard. -Sanitation Department.
我靠！  你他妈的是个倒垃圾的！
Oh, my God! You're a fucking garbage man!
见鬼  四叶·泰背对我和整个美国撒了谎
Damn it. F.L. Tayback lies to me and the whole goddamn U.S. Of A.
我写这书是为了歌颂美军  我是爱国人士！
I wrote the book as a tribute! I'm a patriot!
是啊  你就是爱国者里面假唱的米力瓦利
Yeah, you're the Milli Vanilli of patriots, okay?
你撒谎说参加过越南战争
You lied about fighting the Vietnam War.
你这就像对准美国国旗打了一拳  靠！
It's like punching the American flag in the face, God damn it.
而且我还相信了你！
God, and to think I believed in you!
-我可不想挨着你坐！  -作家们都在说谎
-I don't wanna be next to you. -Writers lie all the time.
能给我绑到另一个柱子上吗？  好吧
Can I be tied to another post? Okay.
-瑞克？  -奋力
-Rick? -Tugg.
我杀了她  瑞克
I killed one, Rick.
世界上我最喜欢的东西
The thing I love most in the world.
维威萨  别听我们谈话
Vivica, get off the line now!
你杀了妓女  好的  你把妓女杀了
A hooker. All right, you killed a hooker.
冷静  接下来这么做
Calm down. Here's what you're gonna do.
手上涂点漂白粉
Get your hands on some bleach,
一些双氧水和一大坨石灰
some hydrogen peroxide and a shitload of lime.
错了  是个熊猫
No, a panda.
我杀了一只熊猫
I killed a panda.
阿曼达？  得了  伙计
Amanda? Come on, dude.
这肯定不是她真名
I mean, that's probably not even her real name.
错了  是只熊猫
No, a panda!
是只熊猫？
A panda?
是只可爱  看着就想抱的
A sweet, cuddly,
邪恶的小熊猫
vicious little panda.
老天  奋力！  别这么吓唬我
Jesus Christ, Tugg! Man, don't scare me like that!
这儿挺漂亮的
It's beautiful here.
你还在外景地吗？
You on the set?
我现在就是外景
I am the set.
别扯了  伙计  那个“替你录”怎么样了？
All right, man. Hey, how's the TiVo working out?
让它去死吧
Screw TiVo.
我不在乎“替你录”了
I'm way beyond TiVo.
我上回去查看  他们还没接好呢
Last I checked, they hadn't hooked it up, though.
没接好？  没“替你录”？
Hadn't hooked it up? No TiVo?
这全都无所谓了
It doesn't matter anymore.
我换地方了
I've moved on.
你换哪去了
Where have you moved on to?
你换了家经纪人公司？
Another agency?
谁跟你在一块？
Who's with you?
你还是我的客户  奋力·快男  我这就帮你搞定“替你录”！
You are still my client, Tugg Speedman! I am getting the TiVo!
我穿上夹克了  马上出门！
Jacket's on, I'm out the door!
奋力？
Tugg?
别解雇我
Please don't fire me.
我的妈呀  渴死了
Oh, mama. Thirsty.
他脸色可不好
He doesn't look too good.
必须喝水  才能呕吐点东西出来
Must drink, so I can throw something up!
别喝那水！  那水像细菌培养皿里的！
No, no. Don't drink that water! That water's like a petri dish!
别喝！
No, don't!
阿尔帕  你还有PP香汗饮料吗？
Alpa, do you have any Booty Sweat?
是啊  让他咕嘟点阿尔帕的屁股汤
Yeah, get him chugging on some of Alpa's ass water.
那能让他恢复意识  那可是万能解药
That'll bring him around. It's a cure-all.
伙计  你干嘛来拍电影？
Man, what you coming out in movies for anyway?
为了多条财路？
Did you need another revenue stream?
你给我听明白  我现在的财路
For your information, my revenue stream
可以让我每年拿出两百万
currently generates $2 million a year
给我的社区做慈善捐助
in charitable contributions for my community.
-真牛B啊  -我为什么拍这部电影？
-Hot damn. -And why am I in this movie?
可能因为我想要做个表率
Maybe I just knew I had to represent,
因为有个好角色是个黑人
because they had one good part in it for a black man
结果还给了“鳄鱼邓迪”
and they gave it to Crocodile Dundee.
你赶紧打住  “鳄鱼邓迪”可是澳大利亚的国宝
Pump your brakes, kid. That man is a national treasure.
“我还想在烤肉架子上添条大虾”
I just wanted to throw another shrimp on your barbie.
这屁话可不好笑
That shit ain't funny.
又热又累  你们别闹了
Hey, fellas! It's hot! We're tired! It stinks!
我就跟你过不去  抢钱袋鼠！
I'm just fucking with you, Kangaroo Jack!
很抱歉野狼吃了你的小孩
I'm sorry a dingo ate your baby.
这是真事儿  那个女士丢了小孩
You know that's a true story? Lady lost her kid.
-你差点就嘲笑过头了  -你们别闹了
-You about to cross some fucking lines. -Guys, relax and stuff.
我他妈的才不管！
You know what? Fuck that, man!
受够了这考拉熊搂着的黑鬼告诉我…
I'm sick of this koala-hugging nigger telling me...
四百年以来
For 400 years,
白人用这词压制着咱们
that word has kept us down.
你他妈说什么呢？
What the fuck?
为了过这个坎  咱们付出了巨大代价
It took a whole lot of trying just to get up that hill.
现在咱们结成联盟
Now we up in the big leagues,
前赴后继
getting our turn at bat.
只要活着  咱们荣辱与共
Long as we live, it's you and me, baby.
这是《杰弗逊一家》的主题歌  你真该看医生了
That's the theme song for The Jeffersons. You really need help.
就算是歌词  也揭示了真相
Yeah. Just 'cause it's the theme song, don't make it not true.
我告诉你什么是真相
You know what? I'm gonna tell you what's true.
真相就是我会报复你的  爱信不信
I'm gonna tag you back. You better believe that, baby.
伙计们  伙计们！
Guys! Hey, guys!
杰夫  离那动物远点
Jeff, stay away from that animal.
我要咬它的皮  我需要…
I'm gonna bite his hide. I need...
我想要把它的胃做成我的紧身衣
I need to wear his stomach skin like a unitard.
大家屁都不准动！
Ain't nobody doing nothing to no one or body!
要是波特牛先生染上了点流感  不想走路
Now, if Mr. Portnoy is feeling a little flu-ish, don't wanna walk,
那就把他放到带蹄子的动物身上
put him up on that cloven-hoof animal!
还要赶路咧
We got ground to cover!
好了  越南战俘营  第67幕戏
All right, POW camp, scene 67.
有本事来啊  考蛋导演！
Bring it on, Cockburn!
我身带枷锁 但是心灵自由
My body may be shackled, but my mind wanders free.
等等 让我再念一次台词
Wait, let me do the line again. Let me do the line again.
我身带枷锁 但是心灵自由
My body may be shackled, but my mind wanders free.
很好 再来一次啊
Good, again. Again.
太好了 接下来是严刑拷打戏
Tugg: Good, good. Now let's do the torture scene.
我在那棵树两边都发现了苔藓
I see moss on both sides of that tree.
看来  不只我一个参加过新兵训练营啊…
Well, you know, maybe if I wasn't the only one at boot camp...
我肚子疼死了  伙计们
My belly really hurts, you guys!
我没开玩笑  我恶心死了
I'm not joking around, I'm nauseous.
放开我  我要吐了！  我可不想像亨德斯那样死
Let me off, I gotta puke! I don't wanna die like Hendrix!
好了  好了
All right. All right.
你还行吗  杰夫？
Are you okay, Jeff?
感觉好极了
I'm awesome.
我靠！
Holy shit!
好了  大家都隐蔽！
Okay. Everyone, down, down, down.
看来我错了
Man. Now I'm tripping.
好像真是剧本上说的越南战俘营
That looks like the POW camp from out the script, yo.
难道快男说对了？
Speedman was right?
我不觉得
I don't think so.
看那些煮东西的大桶和拿枪的守卫
Look at the cooking vats, the armed guards.
看起来像海洛因加工厂
Looks like a heroin processing plant.
咱们在直升飞机上飞了几个小时
We were in that chopper for hours.
我觉得早就不在越南国内了
I don't even think we're in Vietnam anymore.
-靠  -见鬼  咱们都出越南了？
-Fuck. -Shit. We ain't even in 'Nam?
是啊  更像在缅甸和老挝
No, most likely Myanmar or Laos.
老挝是什么东西？
What the fuck is Laos?
是金三角
It's the Golden Triangle.
世界上烈性毒品的集散地
It's the world's hard drug superhighway.
你怎么知道这些？
How do you know that?
旅途太长了  我读了读飞机上的杂志
It was a really long trip. I read the in-flight magazine.
停拍！
Cut!
天哪
Oh, Jesus!
看到了什么？  我被挡住了
What do you see, man? I'm blocked.
戴门  停拍了！
Damien, cut!
戴门  停拍！
Hey, Damien, cut!
他们抓住快男了
They got Speedman.
情况不妙啊
And it doesn't look good.
我是陈老大
I am Tran.
你闯进我的罂粟地盘了
You are a trespasser in my poppy fields.
你们美国缉毒署的混蛋！
You are D.E.A. Scum!
难到重写了剧本我没看见？
Were there some re-writes that I missed?
你想找死吗？
Do you want to die?
-想吗？  -不！
-Do you? -No!
请  别杀杀我！
Please, don't hurt me!
你再说一遍
Say that again.
不要杀我
Please, don't hurt me.
不是  像你刚才那样说一遍！
No! Like you did before! Say it!
说啊！
Say it!
请  别杀杀我！
Please, don't hurt me!
-什么？  -你是笨蛋杰克
-What? -You are Simple Jack.
你看过《笨蛋杰克》？
You saw Simple Jack?
我们喜欢他的故事  笨蛋杰克
We love the tale of this man, Simple Jack.
我们这儿没什么娱乐
We do not have many luxury here.
《笨蛋杰克》是我们仅有的电影
And Simple Jack is the only movie we possess.
噢  是录像带格式的
You got the VHS.
我们看了很多很多遍
We've watched it many, many times.
你应该得奥斯卡奖
You should've got Oscar.
其实  能够…
Well, you know. It's...
能够提名…
Just to be nominated...
你获得提名了？
You were nominated?
没有  我没有获得提名
No, no, no. I wasn't nominated.
我是说  能获得提名就很满足了
I'm just saying that to have been nominated would have been nice.
就…  奥斯卡评选也要搞政治  你得登广告…
It's just... It's very political. You have to take out ads...
-现在闭嘴！  -好的  好的
-Shut up now! -Okay. Okay.
那么  你要
So, are you going to
放我走  还是…
let me go, or...
不行  我们要拿你换赎金
No. We'll hold you for ransom.
现在能要更高的价了！
Much more money now!
他在开会
He's in a meeting.
我知道  2秒钟后他就跟我开会了
Yeah, I know. In about two seconds with the Pecker.
我要把你乳头扯下来
I'm gonna rip your fucking tits off.
想谈谈麻烦事吗？  麻烦来了
You wanna talk about trouble? That's trouble.
哇  哇  哇  哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
想要干什么  佩克？
What do you need, Peck?
不干什么  想要个你正缺的  雷斯
No, more like what do you need, Les?
眼镜？
Glasses?
什么？
What?
这样你就能看清楚《热带惊雷》的合同
So you can read the Tropic Thunder contract
满足我客户奋力·快男  的要求
that guarantees my client, Tugg Speedman,
给他一台数字视频录放机
some form of digital video recorder on location.
-啥？  -你怎么能让他进来
-Huh? -I can't believe you let him in.
听着  傻B  我可是非常忙  你最好快点滚出去
Look, fuckstick, I'm incredibly busy, so why don't you get the hell out of here
省了我扯断你老二塞进你屁股里去
before I snap your dick off and jam it into your ass?
海伦  我刚才没说你
No, not you, Helen.
但你要搞不定那几家电影院  我把你乳头扯下来
But I will rip your tits off if you don't get me those theaters.
正好了
Perfect.
笨蛋奋力  电话现在是用外音喇叭
Hey, Tuggernuts, I've got you on speakerphone.
我正和雷斯·格罗斯曼站在一起
I'm standing here with Les Grossman,
他很想告诉你  为什么把“替你录”条款
and he is dying to tell you why he's apparently wiped his ass
当擦屁股纸的
with the TiVo clause from your contract.
我们是火龙帮
We are Flaming Dragon.
快男现在在我们这儿
Speedman is with us now.
花五千万  你就能把他要回去
For 50 million, you will get him back.
-你能不能把…  -你是谁？
-Are you gonna get those... -Who is this?
-你怎么拿到的电话？  -我们是火龙帮！
-And how did you get this phone? -We are Flaming Dragon!
笨蛋杰克现在在我们手上
Simple Jack belong to us now.
是吗  你想得美
He does, does he?
我跟你说  你个屌毛
Let me tell you something, shitbird.
我从没听说过你们这个破经纪人公司
I've never even heard of your little agency.
可要是你认为能抢走我的客户…
But if you think you can poach my client...
给我五千万  否则跟笨蛋杰克永别  我们就杀了他
Send $50 million, or you no see Simple Jack again because we kill him.
我是雷斯·格罗斯曼  你是谁？
This is Les Grossman. Who is this?
我们是火龙帮！
This is Flaming Dragon!
好的  火龙帮  JB脸
Okay. Flaming Dragon. Fuckface.
你先后退一大步  对着你的脸狠狠地操过去！
First, take a big step back and literally fuck your own face!
我不知道你们代表泛太平洋的
Now, I don't know what kind of pan-Pacific bullshit power play
哪拨装狂的势力  可亚洲和杰克是老子管
you're trying to pull here, but Asia, Jack, is my territory.
别轻易闹事炸刺
So whatever you're thinking, you better think again.
否则  我就过去
Otherwise, I'm gonna have to head down there,
给你们来一场核爆炸天谴
and I will rain down an ungodly fucking firestorm upon you.
到时你们就得给他妈的联合国打电话
You're gonna have to call the fucking United Nations
搞到个解决协议才能让我手下留情
and get a fucking binding resolution to keep me from fucking destroying you.
我说的是烧焦你们  狗娘养的！
I am talking scorched earth, motherfucker!
给你们来场大屠杀！
I will massacre you!
把你们全都搞死！
I will fuck you up!
-能查出来这是谁吗？  -可以
-Could you find out who that was? Go. -Yeah. Yeah.
你们辛苦了
笨蛋杰克
把它戴上  这更像笨蛋杰克的牙
You wear these. More like Simple Jack teeth.
好
Okay.
我明白你是我的超级粉丝  很好…
Hey. Look, I know you're a big fan, and that's great...
把假牙戴上！
Put teeth in!
现在照着电影演
Now do movie.
整部电影？
The whole movie?
演不了  我不知道整个的…
I can't. I don't know the whole...
快演！  不演就杀了你！
You perform! You perform or die!
你个耍猴的！
Monkey swine!
爸
Pa.
再演傻点！
More stupid!
爸  为啥你日日让我这么难受？
Pa, why you gotta make me feel bad?
你们也都看见了
You saw what I saw.
咱们要是不干点啥  奋力·快男就死定了
Tugg Speedman is dead meat if we don't do something soon.
如果快点回到旅馆  还能干点什么
Yeah. We could do something by getting our asses back to the hotel,
可咱们走反了！
which is in the other direction!
不能回去
Ain't right.
如果《大逃亡》里的史蒂夫和伙计们
What would've happened in The Great Escape
就那么退缩逃亡了  该成什么了？
if Steve McQueen and them dudes had turned tail and ran?
可这电影就是拍的逃亡啊  他们最后跑了
Well, that's what that movie was about. They were escaping. They ran away.
你没错  我只是强调他们努力了
I'm trying to agree with you. The point is they did something.
那咱们该怎么办？
Then what are we supposed to do, huh?
'Cause he's cleaning a gun with no bullets. Yeah, that's a plan.
我其实像个心理紧张就开始乱摸鸡鸡的小男孩
I'm just like a little boy, playing with his dick when he's nervous.
大伙等一下  等一下
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我有个主意  可能有点疯狂
I got an idea. This might be a little crazy.
疯主意也比没有强
Crazy's better than nothing.
在98年  我给麦克斯公司拍过低成本色情喜剧
Back in '98, I did a low-budget titty comedy for Skinemax.
-《情色野营》  记得吧？  -记得
-Sex Camp. Remember it? -Yeah.
我们这帮丑男营地队的人
Anyway, me and the campers from the uncool camp
要想办法闯进美女营队的地盘
had to break into the rich girl camp.
我们是这么做的
So, what we did,
用木头和内裤造了一台投石机
we built a catapult out of logs and underwear,
我们被射过围墙  再跳伞着陆
and they shot us over the wall, and we parachuted down.
听着
Look,
伙计们  咱们其实早就有现成计划了
you guys, we already know the plan.
咱们就照着书里面第26章“雨季进攻”那样做
We do it just like in the book, Chapter 26, the Wet Offensive.
《热带惊雷》这本书啊
The book of Tropic Thunder.
你们都看过这书吧？
Yeah, did you guys read the book?
看过外皮儿  书封底  见过照片
The flap, I read the back flap and saw the pictures.
那也没关系  这跟剧本里也一样
Well, it's okay. It's exactly the same as in the script.
酷！
Cool.
你们至少看过剧本吧？
You guys all read the script, right?
我不看剧本演  是剧本照着我演
I don't read the script, script reads me.
这他妈的又是什么意思？
What the hell does that even mean?
你对书和剧本了解多少？  有屁快放！
What you getting at with the books, scripts? Spit that shit out, man!
好吧  “雨季进攻”
All right. The Wet Offensive.
奥西里斯和胖子乔装来吸引敌人注意
Osiris and Fats go undercover as a diversion.
底特律和布鲁克林两人从河塘溜进去
Motown and Brooklyn sneak in via the river.
可他们是训练有素的军人！
Yeah. But those dudes was trained soldiers.
是啊
Yeah!
但咱们是训练有素的演员  你个傻B
And we trained actors, motherfucker.
该开始行动了  我就不说好听的了
Time to man up. And I ain't gonna sugarcoat.
咱们有些人可能会回不了家了
Some of us might not even make it back.
什么意思？  一趟飞机还带不走所有人？
What do you mean? Like not on the same flight?
阿尔帕和我都自带着天然牛B迷彩服
Alpa and I's already wearing earth mama's natural night camo.
-少说不碍事  本森  -抱歉
-Cool it, Benson. -Sorry.
我俩先去侦察  回头大家一起想计划  20分钟还没回  就去找我们
We gonna scout, get a plan together. We ain't back in 20, come looking.
“我们是火龙帮”
We are Flaming Dragon.
好的
Okay.
火龙帮是个制造贩卖海洛因的组织
Flaming Dragon's a heroin manufacturer.
他们负责亚洲八分之一的毒品交易
They're responsible for an eighth of the drug trade in Asia.
-非常高的利润率  -大伙们！
-Huge profit margin. -Guys!
谁能告诉我咱们的计划是什么？
Would somebody please let me know what the game plan is?
佩克  我们尽在掌握中
Peck! We have it handled.
别插嘴  尽在掌握呢
Please, don't interrupt. Everything's under control.
我明白  好的
I got it. Got it.
来电人：笨蛋奋力
-我是雷斯·格罗斯曼  -还没有收到钱
-Les Grossman. -We not get money yet.
现在价钱是一亿了！
Price now 100 million!
现在不交钱  明天笨蛋杰克就死定了
You pay now, or tomorrow Simple Jack die.
好啊  让我先记一下
Great. Let me get this down.
一亿元
100 million.
等等  我有个更好的点子
Wait! I got a better idea.
与其给你一亿
Instead of 100 million,
不如给你送点流浪汉鸡巴奶酪？
how about I send you a hobo's dick cheese?
然后你就杀了他  随你便  扒皮也行！
Then you kill him! Do your thing! Skin the fucking bastard!
玩得尽兴点  玩得尽兴！
Go to town, man! Go to town!
-不行…  -同时  与以往一样
-No... -In the meantime, and as usual,
去操你自己吧
go fuck yourself!
我们从不和恐怖分子妥协
-No. -We don't negotiate with terrorists.
你疯了吗？
hey, are you insane?
-我觉得还能更好点  -很不错了
-I think I could've done that better. -I thought it was good.
他们会杀了他！
They're gonna kill him!
然后我们在新闻发布会上为他掉眼泪
And we'll weep for him, in the press.
以他的名字冠名某个奖学金
Set up a scholarship in his name.
最后  我是说最最后
Eventually, and I'm talking way, way down the road,
起草一个保险索赔书
we file an insurance claim.
最好在年度财务结算之前
Preferably before the end of the fiscal year.
其实  单这个索赔就能补偿电影赔的钱
Actually, the claim alone would net us more than the movie would lose.
你没开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
面对现实吧
Let's face it.
现在小孩们在犹太普林节不打扮成“热天”了
The kids aren't dressing up as Scorcher for Purim anymore.
快男是过气明星
Speedman is a dying star,
像白矮星要变为一个黑洞
a white dwarf heading for a black hole.
物理规律决定  不可避免
That's physics. It's inevitable.
佩克  我们可是给你个大好机会
We've been handed an incredible opportunity here, Peck.
老天要让我们告诉你他的旨意
The universe is talking to us right now.
你必须听从
You just gotta listen.
佩克  这才是精彩部分  也是工作变得有趣的时候
See, this is the good part, Pecker. This is when the job gets fun.
是啊
Yeah.
开口请求神的旨意  然后接受
Ask and you shall receive.
-对  -你先开口  我们配合
-All right. -You play ball, we play ball.
我知道你想要好东西
I know you want the goodies.
欢迎来到好东西的密室
Welcome to the goody room.
注意听  我说的可是给佩克一架G5商用飞机
You paying attention? 'Cause I'm talking G5 for the Pecker.
你就乐得打滚吧
That's how you're gonna roll.
不再有飞机乘客在你耳朵边唠叨了
No more frequent flier bitch miles for my boy.
耶！
Yeah!
我是泡妞高手
Playa.
泡妞高手！
Playa!
大老二的高手
Big dick playa.
老二长过你的膝盖！
Swinging past your knees!
大老二  宝贝儿
Big dick, baby.
是啊
Yep.
要不你就花上5分钟
Or you can grow a conscience
培育良心  然后看它会把你带到哪里
in the next five minutes and see where that takes you.
我就有话直说吧
Let me get this straight.
你要让我15年的客户
You want me to let my client of 15 years,
也是我最好的朋友
one of my best friends,
让他孤独地死在丛林里  就为了G5飞机和钱？
die in the jungle, alone, for some money and a G5?
是的
Yes.
一个G5商用飞机？
A G5 airplane?
是的
Yes.
和一大笔钱
And lots of money.
我是泡妞高手
Playa.
耶！
Yeah!
你就用嘴含住  轻轻舔它  反复摩擦吧！
Smack it up, flip it, rub it down!
可妈妈那么照顾杰克
But Mama take care of Jack a lot.
她还要睡多久才能醒过来？
How many more sleeps before she wakes up again?
对不起  杰克
Sorry, Jack.
她去到天堂了
She in heaven now.
靠！  我还以为那是部烂片
Damn! I thought the movie was bad.
她永远睡睡了
She sleep forever.
是配角的功劳  他实际上缓冲了杰克的傻气
To the man's credit, he's actually eased up on the retard throttle.
达到了某种平衡  这样就吸引住了观众
And now that's added a balance, and the audience can connect.
其实这是演戏的基本常识  不过他还在慢慢磨练
I mean, this is Theater 101, but, you know, he's had a tough road.
以后会更得心应手的
He'll become a naturalist.
-是啊  -雅俗共赏
-Yeah. -Break down the aesthetic distance,
然后…
then the...
跟你说过我会报复你的
Told you I'd tag you back.
我能对你说声道歉吗
Can I tell you that I'm sorry
如果我以前冒犯了你的话？
for any offense I might've caused, man?
-我就是有点摆脱不了…  -成为一个半残？
-I just got caught up in... -In being a dumbass?
我猜是吧
I guess so.
我真不明白你为什么还在演“鸡公乔治”
Why you still doing this Chicken George shit, I have no idea.
-我也不明白  -理解不了
-Neither do I. -It's beyond me.
-我也理解不了  -你自己迷糊了
-It's beyond me. -You confused.
-是有点迷糊  -我知道
-I am a little confused. -I know.
那咱俩就讲和了？
But are we cool?
还没有
Not really.
嘿  伙计
Hey, man.
-进展怎么样？  -还不错  你呢？
-How's it going? -Good. Yourself?
那个  要是影响不了什么
Hey, so, if it's no big deal,
这次任务我就不去了
I think I'm just gonna hang back here for the mission.
我就在旁边看着好了
Watch the stuff.
-这样行吗？  -什么？  不行！
-Is that cool? -What? No!
我们需要你  杰夫
We need you, Jeff.
你这是什么意思？
What are you talking about?
听我说
Okay, look, man.
-我有些事情得告诉你  -好啊
-I got something to tell you. -Okay.
你知道我吃的豆粒软糖吗？
You know those jellybeans I was eating?
其实  不是什么豆粒软糖
Well, they weren't jellybeans, okay?
-是毒品  -真的？
-They were drugs. -Really?
我要是到了毒品宝藏附近  绝对控制不住  会非常想要的
I get down there near the mother lode, I am done. I'm jonesing bad, man.
我会把所有的海洛因都他妈的吸干净
I'm gonna fucking do all the heroin in the fucking world.
你们要真想让事情办成  就把我绑到树上
If you guys wanna make it through this thing, you gotta strap me to a tree.
-你说真的？  -真的  毫不夸张  给我绑到树上
-Are you serious? -Yeah, I'm serious. Literally, a tree.
不管发生什么  完事儿之前也别给我松绑
And you can, no matter what, you can't fucking untie me until it is done,
直到我想都不想了才行
until it is out of my system.
我可能说“伙计们我没事儿了”
I'm gonna say, "Hey, man, I'm cool. It's cool.
“我总算好了  松开我吧”
"I'm finally better. I'm finally better. Untie me."
别听我胡说！  我说什么鸟语都是在骗你！
Don't listen to me! Anything I fucking say is a lie!
一言为定
You got it!
再见  妈妈！
Goodbye, Mama!
现在你能在天堂吃上冰激凌了
Now you can have ice cream in heaven.
今晚我睡觉的时候会在我脑中放的电影里遇见你
I'll see you tonight, when I go to bed, in my head movies.
可这回的电影会让我的眼睛下雨
But this head movie makes my eyes rain.
靠  吉利根的腰被打了
Dang. Short-bus is taking some real hits.
-他们把他带走了  -这可是要折磨他了
-They got him on the move! -That's torture, man.
好  知道他被关在哪儿了
Okay. That's where they keeping him.
我得开始弄我乔装的衣服了
I gotta get cracking on my costume.
你做针线活还行吗？
Say, are you good with a needle and thread?
靠  当然行
Hell, yeah.
在GAP服装店的上个春季“阿尔帕·奇诺”牌棉裤卖了5百万套
Alpa Chino chinos sold more than five million pairs last spring at the Gap.
-图案都是我自己缝的  -咱们走吧
-I sewed them patterns myself, baby. -Let's roll out.
这是树枝做的奥斯卡小金人
It's a little twig man Oscar.
我就叫你小半蹲
I'm going to call you Half Squat.
你可以叫我
And you can call me
爸爸
Papa.
瞧瞧这些星星
Wow, look at all those stars.
真让人感觉自己很渺小
Really makes a guy feel pretty small.
可能是我们最后睁眼看星星的机会了
This could be the last time we look at these stars.
真美啊
Man, that's beauty.
这样的夜晚  能让人反省自己这辈子都为了什么
Nights like tonight make a man wonder what it's all about.
伙计们  谁有杀虫剂吗？
Hey, you guys. Anybody got some bug spray?
别不理我！
Don't ignore me!
坚持到底  伙计  大伙陪着你呢
Stick it out, man. We're gonna get through this.
-喂  柯克  -什么？
-Hey, Kirk? -Yeah?
你还在跟詹妮弗·休伊特约会吗？
Are you still dating Jennifer Love Hewitt?
我觉得她可是超级性感
'Cause I think she's hot.
没有  那都是小报瞎猜的
No, that was just some tabloid conjecture.
伙计们  我挺过来了  把我解开吧
Hey, guys, I'm good. I made it through. You can untie me now.
真够滑稽的
Funny, huh?
演员的生活  一年当中280天都在外面转
The circus life 280 days a year on location.
其实挺难找到一个能忍受这点的姑娘
It's hard to find a girl that can hang with that, you know?
谁也留不住  没办法的事
Not one worth keeping, nohow.
有雷达杀虫剂吗？  埃文？
Hey, Radar? Evans?
我叫凯文
No, it's Kevin.
凯五  不管你他妈的叫什么  给我过来
Kev, whatever the fuck. Come over here.
我没告诉你  肥仔之家  第3屁马上开拍了
I didn't tell you, but Fatties: Fart Three is coming down the pike,
你要是把我解开  我就把一个角色让给你
and there's a role in there for you if you come over and untie me.
杰夫  你得表现坚强点
Jeff, you're just going to have to tough it out.
你妈就是个浑身溃烂的婊子！
Your mother's a cankerous whore!
天哪
Jesus, man.
喂  哥们
Hey, man.
刚才我说你妈是烂婊子的时候？
Remember way back when I said your mother was a cankerous whore?
抱歉  我不是这个意思  她才不是
I'm sorry, man. I did not mean that. She's not.
你呢  伙计？
How about you, man?
明天在家那边有个风骚姑娘等着你吗？
You got some little minx waiting for you on the other side of tomorrow?
等我？
Me?
我都没谈过女朋友…
I've barely even had a girlfriend, and...
我其实特想拍完电影后就能找人上床
I was really hoping I'd get laid when this movie came out,
好像不太可能
but that's not gonna happen.
你呢  爆破小子？
What about you, Masterblaster?
老家那里有你想要得到的人吗？
You got a certain someone you trying to get with back in the States?
阿尔帕·奇诺？  他可是整天整夜都有10个妞陪着
What, Alpa Chino? He's like 10 girls deep, 24/7.
你理解错我的意思了
No. You missing me, man.
我是说的某个特别的人  与众不同的
I'm talking about something special. Big difference.
有吗？
How about it?
有
Yeah.
确实有
Yeah, there is.
有什么内部消息？  你们约会过了吗？
Well? What's the skinny? Y'all been on a date or what?
没有  我…
No. I mean...
我一直想约会  不过可能永远不会有胆子去问
I always wanted to, but I guess I just never had the courage to ask.
事情…很复杂
It's... It's complicated.
得了！  跟做馅饼一样简单
No! It's simple as pie, man.
你在地上站稳了  瞪着她眼睛说
You plant your feet in the ground, you look her square in the eyes, you say,
“宝贝  咱们约会吧” 这就结了
"Hey, baby, you and me's going on a date." That's the end of story.
-她叫什么名儿？  -兰斯
-What's her name? -Lance.
“听我说  兰斯…”
"Listen here, Lance..."
兰斯？  我刚才听成什么了？  兰斯？
Lance? What the fuck did I just hear? Lance?
-你说“兰斯”？  -没有
-Did you say "Lance"? -No!
-听着像兰斯  -我说的是南斯
-That sounded like "Lance." -No, I said "Nance."
-我说南斯  -听着就是兰斯
-That's what I said, "Nance." -It sounded like "Lance."
我可是阿尔帕·奇诺  好吧？
Look, I'm Alpa Chino, okay?
“我爱BB” 明白？
I love the pussy! All right?
屁股坐稳了  看你们的星星
Lay your ass back down and look at the stars.
你写那首“我爱BB”的歌时
When you wrote I Love Tha Pussy
是在想像你的蛋蛋在兰斯脑门上乱晃吧？
was you thinking of dangling your dice on Lance's forehead?
我靠  说什么呢？  得了吧
Oh, hell, no! What? Come on. Look.
-伙计  人人都会有一时的同性恋倾向  -我不是
-Man, everyone's gay once in a while. -I'm not gay!
好莱坞里不稀奇
This Hollywood.
还是聊正事吧
How about we all get back to work?
-好了  行了！  -真是可笑！
-Okay. Cool. -This is ridiculous!
明天还有大事要做  大家别瞎分心
We got a big day tomorrow. Let's get focused.
阿尔帕  你要给我松绑  我现在就去吸你DD
Alpa, if you untie me, I will literally suck your dick right now.
我跟你说最后一遍  我喜欢BB
I told you, for the last time, I love the pussy!
我会捧住蛋蛋  按摩棒棒
I'll cradle the balls, stroke the shaft,
来回运动  咽下肉汁
work the pipe and swallow the gravy.
你赶紧过来  咱们开始做吧
Get it over here, buddy. Let's do this.
好  计划是什么？
Okay, so, what's the plan?
你跟他们说越南话？
Are you gonna talk Vietnamese to those dudes?
不  我说普通话
No. No. Mandarin Chinese.
我听出来他们在这儿说汉语
Which, from what I can tell, is what they speaking down there.
你怎么会说汉语？
How the hell do you know Chinese?
和巩俐演过《丝绸黄金之地》  得了第2个金球奖  第3个奥斯卡
Land of Silk and Money with Gong Li. Second Globe, third Oscar.
为此我花了8个月在北京纺织厂干活体验
Prepped for that one by working in a Beijing textile factory for eight months.
估计这次能成
That might be our ride.
皮带太紧了！
The straps are too tight!
闭嘴  跟着我走
Shut your mouth and follow my lead.
-我无比尊敬你  -是谁啊
别动
冷静冷静  拿着你的鸡鸡
找到一个外国人  在稻田里
老天爷也有差错
发现了另一个外国人  他很肥大
尊敬你  有礼了
有礼了  小蚁王
你在哪里发现这头肥猪的？
昨天
晚上
我发现
他在田里
好的
Okay.
你割稻子在晚上吗？
好的
All right.
看来那里是装弹药的小屋了
That looks like it could be the munitions hut right there.
我到大房子那里找快男
I'm gonna try to find Speedman in the main building.
我错了 是今天早上
我笨 原谅我
我脱水
我需要电解液
我的豆子脑...
塞住了
过来啊！
Get over here!
-你俩怎么在这儿？  -他有手的！
-What are you guys doing here? -He has hands.
-他杀了戴门  -胡说！
-He killed Damien. -Bullshit!
-他还弄瞎了杰米·李·柯蒂斯  -差点弄瞎！
-He blinded Jamie Lee Curtis. -Almost!
你们胡说些什么？  是戴门自己踩上老式地雷了
What are you talking about? Damien stepped on a old landmine.
太好了  谢天谢地
Sweet. Thank God.
-我们这就去救快男  -快男也在这儿？
-We busting Speedman out. -Speedman's here?
闭嘴！
把这个胖子弄下来  拷问他
你滚回家去
我想你们是在演“雨季进攻”那出戏
I take it y'all are doing the Wet Offensive from the book.
我能帮你们转移视线
I can give y'all a diversion.
这一大坨火药估计能把这儿炸得  像国庆节放礼花一样
I got enough shit here to light this place up like it's the Fourth of fucking July.
谢谢你的恩赐
我会很高兴回到我的罂粟田的
等一等！
一开始你说稻田  现在你说罂粟田
我两个都种
我种植多样化
你的农场在哪儿？
我的农场？
是的  你的农场
Yes, your farm.
你说话声音很奇怪
你的农场在哪儿？
Where is your farm,
美国佬？
American?
我的农场？
My farm?
我靠！
Oh, shit.
这他妈的就是我的农场！
Here's my motherfucking farm!
耶！
Yeah!
耶！  咯吱喀嚓  宝贝！
Yeah! Chicka-chickaw, baby!
狂了！
Kwan-Lo!
我是农民头头  王八蛋们！
I'm a lead farmer, motherfucker!
耶！
Yeah!
耶！  耶！  把头低下！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, keep your head down!
把头贴到地上
Keep your head down on the ground!
谁也别动  要不我就干掉这个小老大
Nobody move or I do the little big guy!
干得好  咱们控制局面了  杰夫·波特牛
That's right, we running this program now, J.P.
现在带我去找毒品
Now show me where the drugs are.
你他妈的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
这不在计划里！
That ain't the plan!
别指责我！
Don't judge me!
他的问题可真严重
He's got a real serious problem.
嘿  你！
Hey! Hey, you!
把衣服脱了！
Take off your clothes!
现在怎么办？
What do we do now?
按着计划走  去找快男
Stick with the plan. Find Speedman.
阿尔帕  控制住这群小丑  咱们走
Alpa, keep this clown posse down. Come on now.
听着了吧  都给我温顺的呆好了别动
Y'all heard the man. Be suede, don't move!
你个烂头巾！
Fuck your do-rag. Fuck your do-rag.
-准备开门  -1  2  3！
-Door! -One, two, three!
我去上面  你到下面
I go high, you go low.
趴下  趴下！  周润发们给我趴下
Get down. Get down! Get down! Chow Yun-Fat, get the hell down!
谁敢再抬头  我就一枪打死你个捣乱地鼠
If I see one more head pop up, it's gonna be bullet Whac-A-Mole.
快点  快点
Come on, come on!
-烟雾弹  -别掉地下
-Smoke grenade. -Don't drop it now.
给
Here.
-这是什么？  -不知道叫啥
-What's this? -I don't know what it's called.
我只知道它点着以后  满嘴胡诌是什么声音
I just know the sound it makes when it lies.
别动  火柴盒  要不我打烂你
Don't move, Matchbox, or I will shoot you.
我把这衣服穿上  你别动
I'm gonna put on this thing. Don't move.
我还看得见你
I can still see you.
奋力！
Tugg!
奋力？
Tugg?
找到你啦
Gotcha.
你赶紧卷铺盖走人  咱们回家了
Roll your shit up, man. We going home.
回家？
Home?
可我在这里一天演出5场  场场爆满
But I'm doing five shows a day for a standing-room-only crowd.
你不明白吗？  这里就是我的家
Don't you get it? I already am home.
得了  伙计  你得…
All right, now, dude, you gotta get it...
我儿子送给我的
My son gave this to me.
-这是你的树枝朋友？  -他叫树枝人
-That's your stick buddy? -His name is Twigman.
他想跟咱们一块走吗？
Does he wanna come with us?
给我趴下！
Get the hell down!
你想干啥？  别碰那枪
What you doing? What you doing? Don't touch that gun.
别动  别碰那枪！
Don't do it! Don't touch that gun!
我的妈呀  你要是敢动…
On my momma, if you touch that gun...
-见鬼  开打了！  -从这走！
-Oh, shit, it's on! -Over here!
掩护我  皮诺曹！
Shadow me, Pinocchio!
来点烟雾！
Smoke!
我靠啊！
Oh, shit!
杰夫  别那么做！
Jeff, don't!
我做什么都无所谓了
It doesn't matter what I do.
我这一辈子都是一团糟  没人会瞧得起我了
I'll always be a screw-up. No one'll ever respect me.
你说的不对！  你不是废物！  你让那么多人开心
That is not true, you are not a screw-up! You make so many people laugh.
他们只是在笑我的屁
They only laugh at my farts.
杰夫  咱们得走了！
Jeff, we really need to go now!
我就应该这个下场！
This is all I deserve!
笑个屁  混蛋们！
Laugh at that, you bastards!
好笑吧  好笑吧！
Hilarious! Hilarious!
咱们快走  他们再有16个小时就要醒过来了！
Let's move. We only have 16 hours before they wake up.
看来吃晚饭的铃响了
Sounds like the dinner bell's ringing.
这帮混蛋一会就会爬过来生吃了咱们
These assholes are gonna be crawling in here ready to fucking eat us.
好了  你在这儿望风
There. All right, you keep six right here.
来啊  咱们走了
Come on, let's go.
你们这帮家伙在干吗？  快点走啊！
Come on, what are you guys doing? Let's get out of here!
他正在迷离的状态
He's on tilt status.
在演《月球探测器》的阿姆斯特朗时  我也这样过
Same thing happened to me when I played Neil Armstrong in Moonshot.
他们在澳洲伯班克小路上找到了我
They found me in an alley in Burbank
我正想要乘一个旧冰箱来重新进入大气层
trying to re-enter the Earth's atmosphere in an old refrigerator box.
把火焰喷射器给我  你快去启动直升机
Give me the flame thrower. You gotta start the chopper.
-别管了  去他妈的  交给我  -没时间了  我来顶着
-No, fuck that! Just give me this. -No time! I'll take care of this!
好吧  把你的铁钩给我
All right. Give me your hooks.
别担心了  我不会再戴上了
Don't worry, I'm not gonna put them on again.
-快把铁钩给我  -好  给你
-Just give me your goddamn hooks. -All right. Here.
你快点把这帮孩子带回直升机去啊
Get those boys back to the bird, pronto!
靠啊  够了！
Shit! Enough!
假冒伪劣！
Fake shit!
快去找你的伙计们  带到直升机那儿
Go get your guys! Get them to the chopper!
我来对付这些野蛮人！
I'll take care of these yahoos!
你一定要集中精力  混蛋  跟着我说
You're gonna focus up now, motherfucker, and say it.
-“我是奋力”  -我是奋力
-"It's me, Tugg!" -It's me, Tugg.
好  那奋力是谁？
That's right! Now, Tugg who?
-是谁？  我不知道  你是谁？  -我？
-Tugg who? I don't know. Who are you? -Me?
我知道我是谁！
I know who I am!
我这个家伙要扮演一个  假扮成另一个家伙的家伙
I'm a dude playing a dude disguised as another dude.
啥？
What?
你这家伙连自己是谁都不知道
You a dude that don't know what dude he is!
或者你才是不知道自己是谁的人吧
Or are you a dude who has no idea what dude he is
你还得扮成另一个人…
and claims to know what dude he is...
你们他妈的说什么呢？
What the fuck are you guys talking about?
…才能说出来了解自己？
...by playing other dudes?
我知道我是谁！
I know what dude I am!
-你害怕了  -我没怕  我怕什么？
-You're scared. -I ain't scared. Scared of what?
应该是害怕谁吧？
Or scared of who?
-我怕谁？  -来吧你俩  咱们快走！
-Scared of who? -Come on, guys. We really need to go!
你怕你自己
Scared of you.
-天哪  -到底怎么了？
-Jesus. -What's going on?
全部人格都开始显露出来了
The dudes are emerging.
他说得对
He's right, you know.
我不是
I am not
林肯·奥西里斯  中士
Sergeant Lincoln Osiris.
咱们快走
We gotta roll out.
我也不是神父奥马力
Nor am I Father O'Malley.
也不是阿姆斯特朗
Or Neil Armstrong.
我想我可能谁都不是
I think I might be nobody.
喔！
Wow!
跟你们在一起可真没安全感
The insecurity level with you guys is ridiculous!
-谁都有问题  -是啊  每个人都有问题
-Everybody's got issues! -Yeah, man, everybody got issues.
得了  你可是  柯克·拉扎勒斯
Come on! You're Kirk Lazarus.
就是因为你  我才选择当演员的
You're the whole reason I got into acting.
记得你说过的每一句独白
I memorized every single monologue
我还在戏剧学校时
you ever did when I was in theater school.
-真的？  -还有你  奋力
-Really? -Yeah. And look, Tugg!
我8年级的时候把《热天总动员1》看了24遍
I saw Scorcher I 24 times when I was in eighth grade.
你那电影让我绝对震撼！  爽死我了  你真是个爷们！
That shit blew me away! I got high to that shit! You the man!
是啊  《热天总动员》第一部很不错  咱们快点从这儿离开！
Yeah, man, Scorcher I was great. Let's get the fuck out of here!
奋力  奋力  现在就差你了！
Tugg, Tugger, you're the last piece of the puzzle, buddy.
你的朋友需要你！  你跟我们走吗？
We need you! Your men need you! Are you with us?
我是公鸡做的梦
I'm a rooster illusion.
他妈的  回头对付他
Fuck it. We'll deal with him later.
快点  快点  动作快点  走了
Let's move. Come on. Come on. Double time. Gotta go!
快点  快点  快点
Come on, come on, come on.
太棒了！  开始行动
Bingo! Move out.
噢天啊
Oh, God.
学着对炸药说不  你个贩毒的小矮人
Just say no to this, you drug-making midget.
你要坚持住！
Gotta hold on!
四叶！
Four Leaf!
你长出手来了？
You grew hands?
伙计们  火箭推进式榴弹！
RPG, gentlemen!
你们这是去哪儿？
Where are you going?
天哪  这活干完了我改行开饭馆去
Oh, my God. I am moving to catering after this.
我的屁股！
My ass!
奋力你听着  咱们得快点收拾烂摊子
Hey, yo! We gotta get our shit together, Tugg!
把他这屁神送回直升机去
We gotta get his cracker ass to the chopper!
你还糊涂吗？  咱们得把坎迪斯基带回去
Are you still crazy? We gotta get Candisky to the chopper!
他叫山德斯基
It's Sandusky.
-凯文·山德斯基  -是我名字
-Kevin Sandusky. -That's my name.
你记得我名字
You remembered my name.
阿尔帕  你去帮科迪
Alpa, go help Cody.
波特牛  把山德斯基带回直升机  行动！
Portnoy, get Sandusky back to the chopper. Go!
-好的  -咱们走
-I got him! -Let's go!
快点离开这儿！
Let's get out of here!
嘿  四叶！
Hey, Leaf!
四叶！
-Leaf! -Yeah.
等咱们的人一过桥
Hit the plunger
-你就马上按下这活塞！  -明白
-as soon as they clear the bridge! -Got it!
快点  上直升机！
Come on! Get in the chopper!
-来啊  行动  -柯克！  等等！
-Come on! Move! -Kirk! Wait!
他在干什么？
Jeff: What the hell is he doing?
拉扎勒斯  我就要炸桥了！
Laz, I'm gonna blow the bridge!
四叶就要炸桥了  快！
Leaf's about to blow the bridge. Come on!
你不用救我  我想留下来
You don't have to! You don't have to! I'm staying.
我不能扔下你  咱们一起走
No, I can't let you do that, mate. We gotta go.
我没有发疯  他们会听我解释的
No, I'm telling you, I'm not being crazy. They'll listen to me.
虽然听起来有点怪  可我跟他们有了感情联系
I know it sounds weird, but I have a connection with them.
-快过来！  -我有儿子了  名叫小半蹲
-Get over here! -I have a son now. Little Half Squat.
他妈的又是谁啊？
Who in crikey fuck is Half Squat?
我儿子  我的孩子！
He's my son. He's my boy!
他需要我照顾  我必须回去
He needs me. I have to go back to him.
让外面知道这里发生的事
You tell the world what happened here.
这里发生了什么事儿？
What happened here?
我也说不清楚  不过你得告诉他们
I don't know, but you need to tell them.
我会处理好的
I got this.
奋力！
Tugg!
照顾好大伙  我来和他们说清楚
You take care of the boys! I'll deal with these guys.
他这是去哪？  咱们都要死了！
Where is he going? We're gonna fucking die!
拉扎勒斯  是他自己选择加入马戏团的  走吧
Laz, come on. He joined the circus. Let's go.
-你长出手来了  -是啊
-You've got hands. -Yeah.
-靠！  你本来有手啊？  -快点！
-Fuck! You've got hands? -Come on!
-快点  -进来
-Come on! -Get in!
-快点  -他留下了？
-Come on! -He's staying?
走吧  没希望说服他了  咱们走！
Go! He's a lost cause, mate! Get out of here!
我错了！  快炸桥！  把这破桥炸了！
I was wrong! Blow the bridge! Blow the fucking bridge!
让我来
I got this.
四叶  不！
Leaf, no!
结束了  他死了
It's over! He's gone!
科迪  咱们快走吧
Cody! We gotta go!
快看
Look.
他要不行了
Think he's done.
掩护我！
Cover me!
-得了！  -等等  回来！
-Come on! -Wait, come back!
拿什么掩护他？
How do we cover him?
好了  游戏结束了  伙计咱们走
All right, game over. Come on, mate. Come on.
-你还好吗？  -我身体冰凉
-You all right, man? -I'm cold.
我大腿没知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
瞎扯  腿泡在水坑里了  看着了？  是水坑
No, no, they're in a puddle, mate. See? There's a puddle right there.
-别担心  -太好了
-No worries. -Good.
咱们快点走了  伙计
Come on, we gotta split, man.
-你们回来找我了  -当然了
-You guys came back for me. -Course.
我想跟你说
Hey! I want you to know something.
什么？
What?
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
你是我的好兄弟
You're my brother.
是那种真正的好兄弟
But like a really cool brother, you know?
之间没有任何仇恨和…
Like a brother where there was no animosity or...
眼见为实  你现在真的流泪了
Don't look now, you got some real tears going.
真的？
Really?
这才是能让你获奖的东西
That's the stuff that accolades are made of.
天哪  咱们快走！
Jesus, let's go, man!
好吗？
All right?
起来喽
Upsy-daisy.
快点  快点！  咱们走！
Come on! Come on! Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
进来  进来！
Get in! Get in!
好了  出发吧！
Come on! Here we go!
笨蛋奋力！  我拿到手了！
Tuggernuts! I got it!
-奋力！  -瑞克！
-Tugger! -Rick!
又他妈怎么了？
What the fuck?
我带来了“替你录”！
I got the TiVo!
我朋友想要的“替你录”！
My friend wants a TiVo, my friend gets a TiVo!
我靠！
Oh, shit!
获奖者是…
And the Oscar goes to...
好啊！  奋力·快男
Yes! Tugg Speedman.
《热带蠢雷》  有史以来最昂贵的战争片
"Tropic Blunder, The True Story Behind the Making
“拍摄中的真实故事”
"of the Most Expensive Fake True War Story Ever."
耶！
Yeah!
布鲁克林如愿交了女朋友
你个小杂种！
Yeah, you son of a bitch!
这是阿尔帕的情人兰斯
8项奥斯卡奖  4亿美元收入
Eight Oscars, $400 million
你还挽救了奋力·快男的演艺事业
and you saved Tugg Speedman's career.
所罗门  没有你我肯定做不到
I couldn't have done it without you, Slolom.
真的？
Really?
才不是呢  白痴  没你一样
No, dickhead, of course I could.
-一个阉了的猴子都能顶替你  -哦  我…
-A nutless monkey could do your job. -Well, I...
你去参加派对  喝得酩酊大醉  把功劳都记住自己身上吧
Now, go get drunk and take credit at all the parties.
-我永远不会这么做…  -我在开玩笑
-I would never do that to... -Joking.
-真的？  -真的
-Yeah? -Yeah.
那…太好了  真有你的
Very... Okay, there he is.
-真有你的  好的  -玩得开心
-There he is. Okay. -Go have fun.
好的  我们会很…
All right. We're having a...
不扯了  我真心谢谢你  雷斯  晚安…
Fuck, okay. Thank you, Les. Thank you. You have a good night...
我说真的  阉了的猴子也能顶替你
But seriously, a nutless monkey could do your job.
好的  谢谢您  先生
Good. Thank you, sir.
以下是汤姆·克鲁斯演唱的歌曲
当心！  当心！
来了一个家伙
又来一个家伙
哎呀喔呀！  干嘛对我耳朵
一直说些废话
我才不想听
滚回去  混蛋！  不是熟人  你就别瞎唠叨
喔！  来啊  来啊
小心被打得晕头转向
开着凯迪拉克  不过是小意思
轰走家人  我把毒品包放家里保管
生意还在扩大  日程排得满满
我让钱翻着打滚  就像杂耍
所以我挎着冲锋枪  吓住他们
我腰上的火力比得上鲨鱼攻击
但我没在谈篮球
你们等着打架后  哭着满地找牙
咱们是一类人  你们跑不了了
我刚买了机票  更不跟你废话
所以你们适可而止  迅速走人
否则把你们赶出地盘  脸也打飞
我会给你颜色看看  不再和颜悦色
你们一群傻瓜  别让我爆发
哎呀喔呀！  干嘛对我耳朵
一直说些废话
我才不想听
滚回去  混蛋！  不是熟人  你就别瞎唠叨
哎呀喔呀！  我不是跟你玩闹！
你一招失误  我就把你拿下
滚回去  混蛋！  不是熟人  你就别瞎唠叨
我到来  我见证
出的一拳正中他们下巴
右勾拳困住他们  再来直拳
上勾拳伺候  外加屁股一脚
送他上路了  省了我废话
我不想去郡监狱  因为懒得走路
咱们就像被撞的保龄球瓶  以后扯清
我们以后会盖尽你的风头
给你们脖子上挂个扰乱治安的牌子
然后我们安心点着大麻烟嘴
哎呀喔呀！  干嘛对我耳朵
一直说些废话
我才不想听
滚回去  混蛋！  不是熟人  你就别瞎唠叨
奋力的扮演者  也是本片导演
你得把演员扔到困境里面！
让他们从舒服窝里滚出来！
让咱们拍成这部最伟大的战争电影！
我是农民头头  王八蛋们！
他发信号了  开始！
大地母亲刚被吓得尿了裤子！
噢  不
这可是强力奶头
大地母亲刚被吓得尿了裤子！
我靠  说什么呢？
他妈的怎么回事？
诱饵  我需要诱饵
咯吱喀嚓  耶！
狂了！
我是农民头头  王八蛋们！
妈妈叫我笨蛋杰克
你…日…日…日…让…让我开心
会让我的眼睛下雨
我会捧住蛋蛋  按摩棒棒
来回运动  咽下肉汁
说对了
你差点就嘲笑过头了
我知道我是谁！
我这个家伙要扮演一个假扮成另一个家伙的家伙
把头低下  混蛋！
这游戏就叫这名儿
别指责我！